<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Silicon Valley Real Estate Video Blog with Brett Jennings</title>
    <description>Our mission at Brett Jennings Real Estate Experts is to be your best resource for Silicon Valley real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Brett Jennings Real Estate Experts, your professional Silicon Valley Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 16:08:41 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 16:08:41 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Power of Partnership</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/E7desGiSU0c?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I’m very happy to announce that myself and Olympia Pistalu are combining our businesses into one operation,&lt;/strong&gt; where we’ll bring equal parts enthusiasm and professionalism to better serve your needs this year and beyond!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re unfamiliar with Olympia and her career accomplishments, I’d like to give a brief introduction: She launched in 2016, and in her first year with Coldwell Banker, she earned the designation of Rookie of the Year. She circled around my world this year, and &lt;strong&gt;with the 10 years of experience we bring, there’s added value in us working together.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=With the 10 years of experience we bring, there’s added value in us working together.%20http://localhost:4000/power-of-partnership.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“With the 10 years of experience we bring, there’s added value in us working together.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Olympia cites her confidence that our systems and processes will facilitate her ability to enhance her clients’ experiences and our clients’ experiences overall as a key reason she decided to join the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To that end, the two of us want to be a great resource for you, as it relates to real estate. Therefore, &lt;strong&gt;we’ll be reaching out to you on a regular basis with some of the most relevant information from today’s market.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re thinking about selling your home or you’re curious about your home’s value, click on the “home value” tab. This will give you an instant value of your home. And if you’re considering buying, click on the “home search” tab. This will give you access to all homes for sale in Silicon Valley.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have questions or for help with any and all of your real estate needs, feel free to reach out to Olympia and the rest of our team. We look forward to serving you in 2019!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/power-of-partnership.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/power-of-partnership.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>4 Tips to Help You Hire the Right Listing Agent</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/DBkEKJjhp7U?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can you find the right agent when selling your home? There are four key criteria that you should look out for:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. How much experience do they have?&lt;/strong&gt; Did you know that 90% of home sales are done by 10% of the available real estate agents? Fortunately in today’s market, we do have an online resource that provides transparency to consumers: Zillow. You can see how many home sales an agent has done, figure out who’s doing business by looking at their activity, and find out what it’s like to work with an agent by reading their reviews. From there, pick two to three agents to interview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. What are their specific skills and training?&lt;/strong&gt; Selling a home is a lot different than buying a home and requires a completely different skill set. You should also make sure that your agent has experience in home improvement. Homes that are prepared and updated for the market are selling for 5% to 7% more money than homes that aren’t. An agent with home improvement experience can tell you where to put money into your house in order to get the most money possible out of your home sale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=90% of home sales are made by 10% of real estate agents.%20http://localhost:4000/4-tips-to-help-you-hire-the-right-listing-agent.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“90% of home sales are made by 10% of real estate agents.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Online marketing skills are also incredibly important. These days, 98% of buyers start their home search online. The price your home sells for is a function of how many people see it online and how many of those come to see it in person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, make sure your agent has great negotiation skills. Have they been trained in negotiation? Our agents are all certified negotiators. We also have one of the most innovative real estate teams in the country when it comes to online marketing, and about 75% of our clients have us help them during home renovations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Does the agent have deep resources?&lt;/strong&gt; Preparing a home for sale can be a big job. You may need to get carpeting cleaned or replaced, update the kitchen, or take care of other home improvements. You need to hire someone with a team of resources to take a lot of that work off your plate. Hire someone who can put you in touch with a great mover as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Hire someone you feel comfortable with.&lt;/strong&gt; Selling a home can be stressful. Selling also takes longer than buying a home. Buying a home usually takes about 30 days. Selling can be a 90-day process, so hire an agent that has a great personality. It’s important that you feel comfortable working with this agent for the next two to three months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are happy to help you with any other home selling questions you may have. Just give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 14:16:46 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/4-tips-to-help-you-hire-the-right-listing-agent.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/4-tips-to-help-you-hire-the-right-listing-agent.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>8 Ways to Increase Your Home’s Value on a Budget</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/9IkmOUA4YjU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maximizing your home’s value doesn’t have to cost an arm and a leg. There are eight different ways that you can add up to $50,000 to your home’s value by spending less than $6,000:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Deep clean your home.&lt;/strong&gt; Hire a cleaner that’s going to get all the grease off of your range hood, dust in the areas that you haven’t seen for a while, and get the house looking immaculate. This will make the home feel inviting and give buyers a great first impression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Declutter the home.&lt;/strong&gt; Put away anything that’s smaller than a football that sits on your shelf. Any old, clunky furniture should go in the garage as well. It’s all about maximizing and showcasing the space you have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Paint.&lt;/strong&gt; You don’t need to paint every square inch of every room—you might just need some touch-ups here and there. Make sure everything is in a neutral color.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Update any fixtures or appliances.&lt;/strong&gt; This includes doorknobs, hinges, and switches. These are relatively low-cost updates, but they bring a lot of value to your property. You could spend as little as $500 but add thousands in value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=A home inspection will make sure that no problems are overlooked.%20http://localhost:4000/8-ways-to-increase-your-homes-value-on-a-budget.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“A home inspection will make sure that no problems are overlooked.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Update the landscaping.&lt;/strong&gt; Trim back overgrown bushes, put down some fresh mulch, and plant some new flowers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Small bathroom updates.&lt;/strong&gt; If you have an older bathroom with an older light fixture or vanity, you can get a brand new one for $500 or $600 that will completely update the look of the room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Clean the carpets.&lt;/strong&gt; We work with a few different carpet cleaners that do amazing work and can restore your carpets to just like new. This will probably cost a few hundred bucks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. Have a home inspection.&lt;/strong&gt; There are problems that we can’t see just from looking at the home, but we want to address and fix anything that’s wrong before we get it listed. A home inspection will cost around $750, but it will also help address any deferred maintenance and take any surprises out of the equation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this list or if you want more tips on how to get your home ready for sale, please feel free to give us a call or send us an email any time. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 14:28:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/8-ways-to-increase-your-homes-value-on-a-budget.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/8-ways-to-increase-your-homes-value-on-a-budget.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Can Facebook Help You Sell Your Home?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Yf0AZ0SZbtc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If used correctly, Facebook can be an amazing marketing tool for today’s home sellers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
Considering Buying? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.siliconvalleyrealestatesearch.com/?utm_source=BLOG&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Video+Blog&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for gateway access to MLS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Considering Selling? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.siliconvalleyrealestatesearch.com/home-valuation/?utm_source=VYRAL&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Vyral+Emails+&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.siliconvalleyrealestatesearch.com/off-market-list/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to access off-site properties&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the age of the internet, there are many online resources that can help people sell their homes—but what about Facebook? Can Facebook help you sell?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually, yes. Using a targeted approach, Facebook can allow sellers to double their exposure online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s how it works:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, &lt;strong&gt;ask yourself who the ideal buyer for your property is.&lt;/strong&gt; Defining the profile of your ideal buyer will help you determine what your “avatar” is and how you can market to them. In this case, the term  “avatar” means your target buyer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have this avatar in mind, it’s time to &lt;strong&gt;film and post video footage of your home.&lt;/strong&gt; Videos get the highest level of engagement on Facebook, and are also the most highly prioritized in terms of where they appear on the site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=USING A TARGETED APPROACH, FACEBOOK CAN ALLOW SELLERS TO DOUBLE THEIR EXPOSURE ONLINE.%20http://localhost:4000/can-facebook-help-you-sell-your-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“USING A TARGETED APPROACH, FACEBOOK CAN ALLOW SELLERS TO DOUBLE THEIR EXPOSURE ONLINE.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third step in leveraging this platform to gain exposure for your listing is to &lt;strong&gt;pay for Facebook ads.&lt;/strong&gt; Using Facebook advertising to reach your specific, ideal buyer can vastly increase the amount of attention your listing receives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Facebook is such an effective real estate marketing tool that our team was recently interviewed by The Wall Street Journal regarding this tactic. You can &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/how-real-estate-uses-big-data-to-track-clients-1431615728&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;see the full article here&lt;/a&gt;, but to summarize what we revealed during the interview, &lt;strong&gt;our team was once able to sell a client’s home for $125,000 more than the next-highest offer by using Facebook in our marketing.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bottom line is this: Using Facebook as a tool to help sell your home can be massively effective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 18:26:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/can-facebook-help-you-sell-your-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/can-facebook-help-you-sell-your-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Has The Silicon Valley Market Hit Its Peak?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Pms1tc1LJ1w?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of people have been wondering if the Silicon Valley real estate market has peaked. Today we’re taking a closer look to determine whether that’s the case or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
Considering Buying? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.siliconvalleyrealestatesearch.com/?utm_source=BLOG&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Video+Blog&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for gateway access to MLS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Considering Selling? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.siliconvalleyrealestatesearch.com/home-valuation/?utm_source=VYRAL&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Vyral+Emails+&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.siliconvalleyrealestatesearch.com/off-market-list/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to access off-site properties&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Silicon Valley home prices up by 25% this year already, many area property owners are wondering whether prices can go higher or the market has hit its peak. I’ve got a fall market update for you today that will answer that question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To understand where this market is headed, we have to understand what’s been driving it up in the first place.&lt;/strong&gt; Real estate is a supply-and-demand driven market, but there is an affordability ceiling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For most real estate markets around the country, a balanced inventory means we have about six months of supply. This means that if no other homes came on the market, all the available homes would be bought in six months. &lt;strong&gt;Right now in Silicon Valley, we have only six weeks of inventory available,&lt;/strong&gt; which is actually up 50% year over year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s keeping our inventory constrained? &lt;strong&gt;A few different things.&lt;/strong&gt; First, retirees aren’t moving. In fact, 87% of retirees are staying in their current homes as opposed to relocating or downsizing. Another factor is move-up buyers. Buyers who purchased their home five to 10 years ago and want to purchase a larger home now are facing the prospect of a property tax bill that is double or triple what they’re currently paying. For that reason, these would-be sellers are deciding to remodel or expand instead. Lastly, anyone who has bought a house in the last five years likely has a very low interest rate. If they decide to buy, they will see their interest rate increase almost by 50%. Many are choosing to remodel or expand their current properties, instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=HOME PRICES ARE RISING FASTER THAN WAGES ARE.%20http://localhost:4000/has-silicon-valley-market-hit-its-peak.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“HOME PRICES ARE RISING FASTER THAN WAGES ARE.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What drives demand in real estate? Jobs. In Silicon Valley, there are plenty of them. Last year, 47,000 new jobs were created and 22,000 people moved here. The real issue is that only 12,000 new housing permits were issued, mostly for condos and apartments. &lt;strong&gt;As you can see, we have a low supply and high demand, which has driven the market higher.&lt;/strong&gt; You would think there would be no end in sight, but buyers can only stretch so far, which goes back to the affordability ceiling I discussed earlier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As higher and higher paid workers chase higher and higher priced homes, we get to a point where house prices are going up faster than wages. No matter where you work, you probably didn’t get a 25% raise this year to keep pace with home prices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;59% of tech workers surveyed said they couldn’t afford the house they live in with today’s prices and interest rates. &lt;strong&gt;Only 34% of first-time buyers entering this market can afford to buy a home right now.&lt;/strong&gt; This means that our market hit its peak this summer. We’ve seen prices come off the top by about 6% since this June.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a home seller, it’s a great time to list. Prices are still near all-time highs. If you’re a buyer, inventory is opening up and prices are down a bit. There’s a great window for you to come in and buy your dream home. Either way, the time to buy or sell is now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about the market or want to discuss your buying or selling plans further, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 17:06:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/has-silicon-valley-market-hit-its-peak.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/has-silicon-valley-market-hit-its-peak.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Updates</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>4 Qualities of an Exceptional Buying Agent</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/XUfz2CG9eqY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need a real estate representative for your next home purchase, there are four qualities to look for if you want to hire the best possible agent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
Considering Buying? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.siliconvalleyrealestatesearch.com/?utm_source=BLOG&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Video+Blog&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for gateway access to MLS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Considering Selling? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.siliconvalleyrealestatesearch.com/home-valuation/?utm_source=VYRAL&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Vyral+Emails+&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.siliconvalleyrealestatesearch.com/off-market-list/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to access off-site properties&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes time to buy a new home, how can you be sure that the agent you’ve hired is well-suited for the job?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are four key qualities to look for when evaluating an agent’s fitness for your transaction:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. How much experience does the agent have?&lt;/strong&gt; About 90% of the homes in our market are sold by about 10% of the active agents within it. What’s more is that the average agent only sells between three and five homes every year. A truly experienced agent will be much more active than this. Find someone who is not only very active, but is also providing quality service to their clients. Zillow is a great resource for finding active agents—they have profiles set up on the website, and clients can leave reviews for you to look at. You can even check out our Zillow profile by clicking &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zillow.com/profile/BrettJenningsTeam/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. On average, agents on our team typically sell between 18 and 30 homes a year—five times the number of the average agent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. What negotiation skills does the agent have?&lt;/strong&gt; Most brokerages provide contract training, but training on negotiation isn’t as typical. However, negotiation skills are extremely important, since it’s through negotiation that you can determine how much equity you’ll end up with at the end of your transaction. Everyone on our team is a certified negotiation expert, all taught with the same curriculum used at Harvard Law. We’re very effective in getting our clients homes for the lowest possible price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=EVERYONE ON OUR TEAM IS A CERTIFIED NEGOTIATION EXPERT, ALL TAUGHT WITH THE SAME CURRICULUM USED AT HARVARD LAW.%20http://localhost:4000/what-qualities-do-top-agents-have.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“EVERYONE ON OUR TEAM IS A CERTIFIED NEGOTIATION EXPERT, ALL TAUGHT WITH THE SAME CURRICULUM USED AT HARVARD LAW.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. What resources does the agent have?&lt;/strong&gt; A good buyer’s representative will offer you some off-market properties in addition to what can be found on the MLS. Almost 25% of the transactions that take place today involve homes that never made it the MLS. Those transactions are brokered between the top 10% of agents mentioned earlier. In addition to getting you access to more listings, a top agent can provide other resources like vendor referrals for movers, painters, contractors, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Can you click with their personality?&lt;/strong&gt; Over the course of the transaction, agents and clients tend to form an intimate relationship. We’re helping you build your dream of moving into your new home, so of course you’d want to work with someone you actually enjoyed working with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re in need of an agent to represent you during your next home purchase, we’d be delighted to interview for the opportunity to help you find your dream home, so feel free to reach out us. We’ll be right here, ready to help you create a better life through real estate.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 14:40:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-qualities-do-top-agents-have.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-qualities-do-top-agents-have.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dont Forget These Home Buying Costs</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/PH50JJ66b88?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When buying a home, it’s sometimes easy to forget about certain other costs that come with it. Here are five such costs that you need to remember to budget for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
Considering Buying? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.siliconvalleyrealestatesearch.com/?utm_source=BLOG&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Video+Blog&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for gateway access to MLS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Considering Selling? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.siliconvalleyrealestatesearch.com/home-valuation/?utm_source=VYRAL&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Vyral+Emails+&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.siliconvalleyrealestatesearch.com/off-market-list/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to access off-site properties&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a homebuyer, here are five costs that often get forgotten about that you need to remember to budget for:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. The down payment.&lt;/strong&gt; Most people don’t actually forget the down payment, but they forget about what kind of difference how much you put down makes. In our area, you can put down as little as 3% for any property up to $700,000. Above that price, you usually have to put down a minimum of 10%. To get the best interest rate from your lender, you’ll have to put down 20% or more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Your financial reserves.&lt;/strong&gt; You’ll need at least six months’ worth of mortgage payments and property tax payments saved up when you buy a home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Moving expenses.&lt;/strong&gt; Unless you’re doing it all yourself (which I don’t recommend), moving isn’t cheap. A good moving company usually costs between $2,500 and $4,000, and we can refer you to several movers who will take great care of you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=UNLESS YOU’RE DOING IT ALL YOURSELF, MOVING ISN’T CHEAP.%20http://localhost:4000/dont-forget-these-home-buying-costs.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“UNLESS YOU’RE DOING IT ALL YOURSELF, MOVING ISN’T CHEAP.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Furniture.&lt;/strong&gt; Buying a new home is exciting, and once you move in, odds are you’ll want to fix it up exactly the way you want it. This usually means buying new furniture. Also, don’t forget about the essential items you might need to buy, like a new broom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Home updates.&lt;/strong&gt; If your new home has an old bathroom that you want to fix up, you’ll have to budget for that. How much this will cost you can vary, so we’d be happy to come to your home, give you an estimate, and recommend some excellent contractors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any more questions about these costs or you have any other real estate needs, feel free to give me a call or shoot me an email. I’d be happy to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 11:10:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/dont-forget-these-home-buying-costs.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/dont-forget-these-home-buying-costs.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Sell Your Home for 18% More Money Part 5: Negotiations</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/QFhH9wsQ_uI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In today’s fifth and final installment into our latest series, we’ll be discussing the last component of earning more money for your home: Negotiations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
Considering Buying? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.siliconvalleyrealestatesearch.com/?utm_source=BLOG&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Video+Blog&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for gateway access to MLS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Considering Selling? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.siliconvalleyrealestatesearch.com/home-valuation/?utm_source=VYRAL&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Vyral+Emails+&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.siliconvalleyrealestatesearch.com/off-market-list/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to access off-site properties&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=HAVING A SKILLED NEGOTIATOR WHO CAN THINK OUTSIDE THE BOX WILL BE VERY HELPFUL FOR YOU IN ANY REAL ESTATE SCENARIO.%20http://localhost:4000/how-to-sell-your-home-for-18-more-money.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“HAVING A SKILLED NEGOTIATOR WHO CAN THINK OUTSIDE THE BOX WILL BE VERY HELPFUL FOR YOU IN ANY REAL ESTATE SCENARIO.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are four strategies that I recommend all sellers employ when it comes time to negotiate a deal for their home sale. These strategies are the last piece of the puzzle in earning 18% more for your property when it comes time to sell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Encourage preemptive offers.&lt;/strong&gt; This strategy entails capturing interested buyers before your home technically hits the multiple listing service by marketing it as “coming soon.” Typically, it’s advisable to put a list price that’s higher than your expectation at this point in the process. I can tell you from experience that because of our low inventory, buyers are tired of getting beaten out and will be willing submit a preemptive offer that is at or above your price expectation when you follow this strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Price for multiple offers.&lt;/strong&gt; If you didn’t earn the price you’d hoped for during the “coming soon” phase of your listing process, it’s time to price your home in a way that represents a great value and encourages multiple offers. When buyers see your listing as an exceptional deal, they will be more likely to compete over it. This will ultimately drive up the price and help you net more for your home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Determine your best alternative to a negotiated agreement (BATNA).&lt;/strong&gt; More simply put, this strategy essentially serves as the “Plan B” you should fall onto in the event that your original negotiated agreement is somehow compromised. This will ensure that if anything unexpected happens during the course of the deal, you will still have an idea of how you’d like to proceed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Be creative.&lt;/strong&gt; If you’re close to getting the results you want but just aren’t there yet, you should consult with your agent about possible solutions. As an example, we had a seller recently whose minimum bottom line for their home was $1 million, but whose buyer had a loan approval that was maxed out at $990,000. To compensate for this $10,000 disparity, we advised the seller to credit the buyer with $5,000, with the understanding that the credit was to be explicitly dedicated toward lowering the buyer’s interest rate on their loan. The buyer was able to lower their interest rate from 4.25% to 4%, which raised their mortgage approval up to just over $1 million. As a result, the buyer was able to secure the home and the seller was able to net their desired price. Having a skilled negotiator who can think outside the box will be very helpful for you in any real estate scenario.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, the bottom line is that doing many little things right throughout a transaction can make a big difference in your success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 10:31:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-sell-your-home-for-18-more-money.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-to-sell-your-home-for-18-more-money.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Win a Multiple Offer Situation: Part 1</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/hsKGmrXw3Sc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having the right financing is essential to winning a multiple offer situation, and today we’ll discuss three pieces of advice related to this point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
Considering Buying? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.siliconvalleyrealestatesearch.com/?utm_source=BLOG&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Video+Blog&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for gateway access to MLS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Considering Selling? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.siliconvalleyrealestatesearch.com/home-valuation/?utm_source=VYRAL&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Vyral+Emails+&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.siliconvalleyrealestatesearch.com/off-market-list/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to access off-site properties&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today’s market is extremely competitive for buyers. So when they’re up against multiple bids from other buyers on the same house, what can they do to make their offer stand out? Today’s topic marks the first installment of my series that addresses that very conundrum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our team’s preferred lender, Michael Treon, is going to help me cover the answer to this. Let’s kick off our discussion with three things buyers should do to set themselves up for success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Get fully approved.&lt;/strong&gt; Winning in a multiple offer situation starts with getting the right financing in place. Getting fully approved and underwritten, not just pre-approved, is essential. A full approval will allow you to be competitive in the marketplace because it eliminates the need for you to include a loan contingency on your offers. Today’s sellers are looking for the cleanest possible offers because they want to close quickly and without issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=WINNING IN A MULTIPLE OFFER SITUATION STARTS WITH GETTING THE RIGHT FINANCING IN PLACE.%20http://localhost:4000/how-to-win-multiple-offer-situation.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“WINNING IN A MULTIPLE OFFER SITUATION STARTS WITH GETTING THE RIGHT FINANCING IN PLACE.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Select a lender who can provide financing the performs like cash in the market.&lt;/strong&gt; Over 30% of buyers in today’s market are submitting all-cash offers. These offers easily win out against those with conventional loan financing because they allow a shorter close of escrow. Therefore, it’s very important that the offer you submit can stack up against ones such as this. Michael Treon and his team are able to provide buyers with financing that allows for an exceptionally fast close of just 17 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Consider all loan options.&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t limit yourself by looking exclusively at 30-year fixed mortgages. The reality is that most homeowners won’t stay in a property for the full 30 years, so it’s critical to consider alternative loan options. There are a lot of opportunities to secure a home with a loan product that makes sense for your personal circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you understand how the right financing can boost your success in multiple offer situations, be on the lookout for part two of our series. Next time, we’ll talk about how to access off-market properties, and how doing so can help you find a home in today’s competitive market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To view Michael Treon’s mortgage pre-approval process, click &lt;a href=&quot;http://pncmortgage.com/michaeltreon&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/pnc.jpg&quot; class=&quot;png-logo&quot; /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Michael Treon&lt;/strong&gt;, Senior Mortgage Loan Officer&lt;br /&gt;
PNC Bank | NMLS ID: 339550&lt;br /&gt;
michael.treon@pnc.com | pncmortgage.com/michaeltreon&lt;br /&gt;
(Office) 415.505.7558 | (f) 844.274.9911&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 16:47:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-win-multiple-offer-situation.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-to-win-multiple-offer-situation.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Another Way to Net Up to 18% More for Your Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/i_WCW88vtio?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marketing is a key step to net up to 18% more for your home. Today I’d like to go over four areas of marketing you must focus on to optimize your results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
Considering Buying? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.siliconvalleyrealestatesearch.com/?utm_source=BLOG&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Video+Blog&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for gateway access to MLS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Considering Selling? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.siliconvalleyrealestatesearch.com/home-valuation/?utm_source=VYRAL&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Vyral+Emails+&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.siliconvalleyrealestatesearch.com/off-market-list/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to access off-site properties&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’m back with the fourth installment into our series on how you can sell your home for 18% more money. I know this sounds like a bold claim, but it’s true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In previous episodes we talked about preparing, presenting, and pricing your home. This time we’ll be talking about the importance of marketing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marketing controls how many people see the home, both online and in person, and this exposure is what will dictate what the property sells for. To achieve optimal results, there are four main areas of marketing you must focus on:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Local marketing.&lt;/strong&gt; This involves placing your property on the local MLS, which is syndicated to over 200 different websites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=MARKETING CONTROLS HOW MANY PEOPLE SEE THE HOME, BOTH ONLINE AND IN PERSON, AND THIS EXPOSURE IS WHAT WILL DICTATE WHAT THE PROPERTY SELLS FOR.%20http://localhost:4000/another-way-to-earn-more-for-your.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“MARKETING CONTROLS HOW MANY PEOPLE SEE THE HOME, BOTH ONLINE AND IN PERSON, AND THIS EXPOSURE IS WHAT WILL DICTATE WHAT THE PROPERTY SELLS FOR.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. National marketing.&lt;/strong&gt; Silicon Valley is a major relocation destination, so marketing your listing across the country could help you capture an out-of-state buyer. Websites like Zillow, Trulia, and Realtor.com will be some of your best resources in gaining national exposure. Our team allocates a lot of our marketing expenses into making sure our clients’ listings appear at the top of online searches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. International marketing.&lt;/strong&gt; 31% of all property purchases in our state are either foreign or foreign-born. Therefore, it’s important not to miss out on this segment of the market. Our team has partnered with Proxio, a platform that allows us to connect and engage with over 100 different countries using 82 different websites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Social media marketing.&lt;/strong&gt; The internet is an incredible tool. In fact, Facebook could bring you nearly twice the exposure you’d get on Zillow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2018 12:01:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/another-way-to-earn-more-for-your.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/another-way-to-earn-more-for-your.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Selling Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
