<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Silicon Valley Real Estate Video Blog with Brett Jennings</title>
    <description>Our mission at Brett Jennings Real Estate Experts is to be your best resource for Silicon Valley real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Brett Jennings Real Estate Experts, your professional Silicon Valley Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 13:45:46 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 13:45:46 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Sell Your Home Without a Realtor</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Lq9fJtQ25Ao?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we’re real estate professionals ourselves, you may be wondering why we’d want to tell you how to sell a home without us. Because we’re in such a hot market, plenty of people have been asking us how to sell a home on their own, so we figured we’d provide the information for doing so. &lt;strong&gt;Here are the five steps for selling your home without a Realtor:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Prepare your home for the market.&lt;/strong&gt; Well-prepared homes are selling for 5% to 7% more than unprepared homes. Clean up your home, declutter, and paint rooms that you feel need it. Keep in mind that the money you put into preparing the property will often yield a 200% to 300% return when you sell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Market your home.&lt;/strong&gt; Zillow is one of the biggest online marketplaces for homes, and over 50% of buyers are going to this site when beginning their home search. Zillow will allow you to post your home for free, but you also want to take advantage of the multiple listing service (MLS). With a quick search online, you can find services that will list your home on the MLS without an agent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Retain counsel for help with the paperwork.&lt;/strong&gt; A good real estate attorney will help you with contracts and disclosures. There are a number of legally required disclosures in California, and if you miss any, you’re putting yourself at risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Have good negotiation skills.&lt;/strong&gt; Once the offers come in on your home, you want to be able to negotiate with the buyers. If your negotiating skills aren’t so great, you can always lean on your real estate attorney to help out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=One of the biggest things we do as professional Realtors is help you get more money for your sale.%20http://localhost:4000/how-to-sell-your-home-without-a-realtor.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“One of the biggest things we do as professional Realtors is help you get more money for your sale.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Get post-sale protection.&lt;/strong&gt; Title insurance is often required when you take out a mortgage loan with your bank. We recommend you purchase a home warranty—if anything goes wrong in the year following the buyer’s purchase of your home, it’s covered by the warranty. Both of these minimize legal issues you may encounter down the road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following these steps will help you sell your home, but it may not sell for top dollar. One of the biggest things we do as professional Realtors is help you get more money for your sale. Here’s a funny story: The founder of ForSaleByOwner.com listed his home on his own site and related sites, but it went unsold for six months. After finding no luck through his own resources, he hired a Realtor and sold it for more than asking price. It just goes to show that a good Realtor can go a long way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re considering selling your home, let us demonstrate what we can do for you. We have a market-proven process that is guaranteed to get your home sold for more money—up to 18% more than the neighborhood average. Feel free to reach out to us if you’d like a consultation, have any questions, or need more information. We look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 14:08:36 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-sell-your-home-without-a-realtor.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-to-sell-your-home-without-a-realtor.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Ways to Make Your Home Shine</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/oMic3vFpWPk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are really five key things to think about when it comes to sprucing up your curb appeal:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Spruce up your landscaping.&lt;/strong&gt; Go through the front of the property and trim back any bushes or trees that need pruning. Put some nice, fresh, colorful flowers in the flowerbeds, and then add mulch or bark to any areas of exposed dirt to create a nice, crisp line between any concrete or grass and the flowerbed. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Pressure-wash the exterior of the home.&lt;/strong&gt; If you don’t have a pressure washer, there is the option of renting one or else borrowing one from the Brett Jennings Real Estate Experts—we do allow clients and potential clients to use it, so feel free to ask.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If you are repainting, you might also think about changing the color, since some colors might be more en vogue than what you currently have.%20http://localhost:4000/5-ways-to-make-your-home-shine.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If you are repainting, you might also think about changing the color, since some colors might be more en vogue than what you currently have.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Paint the exterior if necessary.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s probably been a number of years since you’ve last painted your home, if you ever have at all. Consider repainting the exterior to give your home a crisp look. If you are repainting, you might also think about changing the color, since some colors might be more en vogue than what you currently have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Update your home’s accents.&lt;/strong&gt; Such accents include your shutters and exterior light fixtures like wall sconces. These are relatively inexpensive and easy to change out, and they can give your home an updated look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Focus on the front door and garage door.&lt;/strong&gt; We never get a second chance to make a first impression, and a nice front door and garage door can give your home an added pop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully these tips will give you a better idea of how to make your home more attractive to both passersby and to potential buyers. If you have any more questions about maximizing your home’s curb appeal, we’d be happy to come take a look at your home and create a customized plan for you at no cost. Feel free to reach out to us. We hope to hear from you soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 12:54:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/5-ways-to-make-your-home-shine.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/5-ways-to-make-your-home-shine.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Is Zillow’s Zestimate Feature Costing You Money?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/7q9ckXrmY8Y?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The big questions for today are: What is a Zestimate, how accurate is it, and how can you make sure that it’s not costing you money?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is a Zestimate?&lt;/strong&gt; Well, the Zestimate is just an automated valuation model that’s derived from an algorithm that incorporates basic, public information about your home and other homes in the area to come up with an estimated value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is the Zestimate accurate?&lt;/strong&gt; Well, Zillow’s own website admits that the Zestimate can be anywhere from 10% to 20% off the market value of a home. It really only is meant to be a starting point. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What affects the value of a Zestimate?&lt;/strong&gt; The algorithm used to value a home is based on the specifics of your home, like your bed and bath count, the market trends in your area, or how much the aggregate value of your zip code has increased; and it also looks at recent or past sales. If you’ve sold your home recently for below market value, your home’s Zestimate will be a little undervalued until a certain amount of time has passed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If you want a more accurate estimate of your home’s value, I strongly advise you to enlist the help of a local Realtor to do a broker price opinion, or else to hire an appraiser.%20http://localhost:4000/is-zillows-zestimate-feature-costing-you-money.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If you want a more accurate estimate of your home’s value, I strongly advise you to enlist the help of a local Realtor to do a broker price opinion, or else to hire an appraiser.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because Zillow only uses basic information to calculate your Zestimate, &lt;strong&gt;there are certain things that the website can’t factor in, such as:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your home’s upgrades&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Distinct features of your home, like views, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Any additions you’ve made to the property&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a homeowner, here’s what I suggest you do in order to insulate yourself:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Find your Zestimate online and claim your home.&lt;/strong&gt; Zillow does allow you to audit the specifications of your home and add in certain features the site will have missed. However, the most important thing to do is to make sure your bed/bath count and your square footage of both your home and your lot are recorded accurately. At least then you’ll know that you’ll get Zillow’s best estimate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want a more accurate estimate of your home’s value, I strongly advise you to enlist the help of a local Realtor to do a broker price opinion, or else to hire an appraiser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In that case, give the Brett Jennings Group a call. We can do a free assessment of your property, and while we’re there, we can also give you some tips and ideas on what you can do to increase the value of your home with some simple upgrades and fix-ups before you bring it to market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like more details on increasing your home’s value, check out one of our other video blogs called “&lt;a href=&quot;https://siliconvalleyrealestatejournal.com/silicon-valley-real-estate-home.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;5 Tips to Boost Your Home’s Value.&lt;/a&gt;” It is one of our most popular blogs. We hope to hear from you soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 16:37:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/is-zillows-zestimate-feature-costing-you-money.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/is-zillows-zestimate-feature-costing-you-money.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Power of Partnership</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/9sXL2_WJ0ls?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://olympia.siliconvalleyrealestatesearch.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/hs.png&quot; class=&quot;photo-cta&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://olympia.siliconvalleyrealestatesearch.com/home-valuation/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/hv.png&quot; class=&quot;photo-cta&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I’m very happy to announce that myself and Olympia Pistalu are combining our businesses into one operation,&lt;/strong&gt; where we’ll bring equal parts enthusiasm and professionalism to better serve your needs this year and beyond!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re unfamiliar with Olympia and her career accomplishments, I’d like to give a brief introduction: She launched in 2016, and in her first year with Coldwell Banker, she earned the designation of Rookie of the Year. She circled around my world this year, and &lt;strong&gt;with the 10 years of experience we bring, there’s added value in us working together.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=With the 10 years of experience we bring, there’s added value in us working together.%20http://localhost:4000/power-of-partnership.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“With the 10 years of experience we bring, there’s added value in us working together.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Olympia cites her confidence that our systems and processes will facilitate her ability to enhance her clients’ experiences and our clients’ experiences overall as a key reason she decided to join the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To that end, the two of us want to be a great resource for you, as it relates to real estate. Therefore, &lt;strong&gt;we’ll be reaching out to you on a regular basis with some of the most relevant information from today’s market.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re thinking about selling your home or you’re curious about your home’s value, click on the “home value” tab. This will give you an instant value of your home. And if you’re considering buying, click on the “home search” tab. This will give you access to all homes for sale in Silicon Valley.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have questions or for help with any and all of your real estate needs, feel free to reach out to Olympia and the rest of our team. We look forward to serving you in 2019!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/power-of-partnership.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/power-of-partnership.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>4 Tips to Help You Hire the Right Listing Agent</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/SgHcN8HKP9Y?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can you find the right agent when selling your home? There are four key criteria that you should look out for:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. How much experience do they have?&lt;/strong&gt; Did you know that 90% of home sales are done by 10% of the available real estate agents? Fortunately in today’s market, we do have an online resource that provides transparency to consumers: Zillow. You can see how many home sales an agent has done, figure out who’s doing business by looking at their activity, and find out what it’s like to work with an agent by reading their reviews. From there, pick two to three agents to interview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. What are their specific skills and training?&lt;/strong&gt; Selling a home is a lot different than buying a home and requires a completely different skill set. You should also make sure that your agent has experience in home improvement. Homes that are prepared and updated for the market are selling for 5% to 7% more money than homes that aren’t. An agent with home improvement experience can tell you where to put money into your house in order to get the most money possible out of your home sale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=90% of home sales are made by 10% of real estate agents.%20http://localhost:4000/4-tips-to-help-you-hire-the-right-listing-agent.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“90% of home sales are made by 10% of real estate agents.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Online marketing skills are also incredibly important. These days, 98% of buyers start their home search online. The price your home sells for is a function of how many people see it online and how many of those come to see it in person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, make sure your agent has great negotiation skills. Have they been trained in negotiation? Our agents are all certified negotiators. We also have one of the most innovative real estate teams in the country when it comes to online marketing, and about 75% of our clients have us help them during home renovations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Does the agent have deep resources?&lt;/strong&gt; Preparing a home for sale can be a big job. You may need to get carpeting cleaned or replaced, update the kitchen, or take care of other home improvements. You need to hire someone with a team of resources to take a lot of that work off your plate. Hire someone who can put you in touch with a great mover as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Hire someone you feel comfortable with.&lt;/strong&gt; Selling a home can be stressful. Selling also takes longer than buying a home. Buying a home usually takes about 30 days. Selling can be a 90-day process, so hire an agent that has a great personality. It’s important that you feel comfortable working with this agent for the next two to three months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are happy to help you with any other home selling questions you may have. Just give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 14:16:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/4-tips-to-help-you-hire-the-right-listing-agent.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/4-tips-to-help-you-hire-the-right-listing-agent.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>8 Ways to Increase Your Home’s Value on a Budget</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/9IkmOUA4YjU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maximizing your home’s value doesn’t have to cost an arm and a leg. There are eight different ways that you can add up to $50,000 to your home’s value by spending less than $6,000:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Deep clean your home.&lt;/strong&gt; Hire a cleaner that’s going to get all the grease off of your range hood, dust in the areas that you haven’t seen for a while, and get the house looking immaculate. This will make the home feel inviting and give buyers a great first impression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Declutter the home.&lt;/strong&gt; Put away anything that’s smaller than a football that sits on your shelf. Any old, clunky furniture should go in the garage as well. It’s all about maximizing and showcasing the space you have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Paint.&lt;/strong&gt; You don’t need to paint every square inch of every room—you might just need some touch-ups here and there. Make sure everything is in a neutral color.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Update any fixtures or appliances.&lt;/strong&gt; This includes doorknobs, hinges, and switches. These are relatively low-cost updates, but they bring a lot of value to your property. You could spend as little as $500 but add thousands in value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=A home inspection will make sure that no problems are overlooked.%20http://localhost:4000/8-ways-to-increase-your-homes-value-on-a-budget.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“A home inspection will make sure that no problems are overlooked.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Update the landscaping.&lt;/strong&gt; Trim back overgrown bushes, put down some fresh mulch, and plant some new flowers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Small bathroom updates.&lt;/strong&gt; If you have an older bathroom with an older light fixture or vanity, you can get a brand new one for $500 or $600 that will completely update the look of the room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Clean the carpets.&lt;/strong&gt; We work with a few different carpet cleaners that do amazing work and can restore your carpets to just like new. This will probably cost a few hundred bucks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. Have a home inspection.&lt;/strong&gt; There are problems that we can’t see just from looking at the home, but we want to address and fix anything that’s wrong before we get it listed. A home inspection will cost around $750, but it will also help address any deferred maintenance and take any surprises out of the equation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this list or if you want more tips on how to get your home ready for sale, please feel free to give us a call or send us an email any time. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 14:28:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/8-ways-to-increase-your-homes-value-on-a-budget.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/8-ways-to-increase-your-homes-value-on-a-budget.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Can Facebook Help You Sell Your Home?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Yf0AZ0SZbtc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If used correctly, Facebook can be an amazing marketing tool for today’s home sellers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
Considering Buying? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.siliconvalleyrealestatesearch.com/?utm_source=BLOG&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Video+Blog&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for gateway access to MLS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Considering Selling? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.siliconvalleyrealestatesearch.com/home-valuation/?utm_source=VYRAL&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Vyral+Emails+&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.siliconvalleyrealestatesearch.com/off-market-list/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to access off-site properties&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the age of the internet, there are many online resources that can help people sell their homes—but what about Facebook? Can Facebook help you sell?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually, yes. Using a targeted approach, Facebook can allow sellers to double their exposure online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s how it works:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, &lt;strong&gt;ask yourself who the ideal buyer for your property is.&lt;/strong&gt; Defining the profile of your ideal buyer will help you determine what your “avatar” is and how you can market to them. In this case, the term  “avatar” means your target buyer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have this avatar in mind, it’s time to &lt;strong&gt;film and post video footage of your home.&lt;/strong&gt; Videos get the highest level of engagement on Facebook, and are also the most highly prioritized in terms of where they appear on the site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=USING A TARGETED APPROACH, FACEBOOK CAN ALLOW SELLERS TO DOUBLE THEIR EXPOSURE ONLINE.%20http://localhost:4000/can-facebook-help-you-sell-your-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“USING A TARGETED APPROACH, FACEBOOK CAN ALLOW SELLERS TO DOUBLE THEIR EXPOSURE ONLINE.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third step in leveraging this platform to gain exposure for your listing is to &lt;strong&gt;pay for Facebook ads.&lt;/strong&gt; Using Facebook advertising to reach your specific, ideal buyer can vastly increase the amount of attention your listing receives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Facebook is such an effective real estate marketing tool that our team was recently interviewed by The Wall Street Journal regarding this tactic. You can &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/articles/how-real-estate-uses-big-data-to-track-clients-1431615728&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;see the full article here&lt;/a&gt;, but to summarize what we revealed during the interview, &lt;strong&gt;our team was once able to sell a client’s home for $125,000 more than the next-highest offer by using Facebook in our marketing.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bottom line is this: Using Facebook as a tool to help sell your home can be massively effective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 18:26:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/can-facebook-help-you-sell-your-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/can-facebook-help-you-sell-your-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Has The Silicon Valley Market Hit Its Peak?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Pms1tc1LJ1w?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of people have been wondering if the Silicon Valley real estate market has peaked. Today we’re taking a closer look to determine whether that’s the case or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
Considering Buying? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.siliconvalleyrealestatesearch.com/?utm_source=BLOG&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Video+Blog&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for gateway access to MLS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Considering Selling? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.siliconvalleyrealestatesearch.com/home-valuation/?utm_source=VYRAL&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Vyral+Emails+&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.siliconvalleyrealestatesearch.com/off-market-list/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to access off-site properties&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Silicon Valley home prices up by 25% this year already, many area property owners are wondering whether prices can go higher or the market has hit its peak. I’ve got a fall market update for you today that will answer that question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To understand where this market is headed, we have to understand what’s been driving it up in the first place.&lt;/strong&gt; Real estate is a supply-and-demand driven market, but there is an affordability ceiling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For most real estate markets around the country, a balanced inventory means we have about six months of supply. This means that if no other homes came on the market, all the available homes would be bought in six months. &lt;strong&gt;Right now in Silicon Valley, we have only six weeks of inventory available,&lt;/strong&gt; which is actually up 50% year over year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s keeping our inventory constrained? &lt;strong&gt;A few different things.&lt;/strong&gt; First, retirees aren’t moving. In fact, 87% of retirees are staying in their current homes as opposed to relocating or downsizing. Another factor is move-up buyers. Buyers who purchased their home five to 10 years ago and want to purchase a larger home now are facing the prospect of a property tax bill that is double or triple what they’re currently paying. For that reason, these would-be sellers are deciding to remodel or expand instead. Lastly, anyone who has bought a house in the last five years likely has a very low interest rate. If they decide to buy, they will see their interest rate increase almost by 50%. Many are choosing to remodel or expand their current properties, instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=HOME PRICES ARE RISING FASTER THAN WAGES ARE.%20http://localhost:4000/has-silicon-valley-market-hit-its-peak.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“HOME PRICES ARE RISING FASTER THAN WAGES ARE.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What drives demand in real estate? Jobs. In Silicon Valley, there are plenty of them. Last year, 47,000 new jobs were created and 22,000 people moved here. The real issue is that only 12,000 new housing permits were issued, mostly for condos and apartments. &lt;strong&gt;As you can see, we have a low supply and high demand, which has driven the market higher.&lt;/strong&gt; You would think there would be no end in sight, but buyers can only stretch so far, which goes back to the affordability ceiling I discussed earlier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As higher and higher paid workers chase higher and higher priced homes, we get to a point where house prices are going up faster than wages. No matter where you work, you probably didn’t get a 25% raise this year to keep pace with home prices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;59% of tech workers surveyed said they couldn’t afford the house they live in with today’s prices and interest rates. &lt;strong&gt;Only 34% of first-time buyers entering this market can afford to buy a home right now.&lt;/strong&gt; This means that our market hit its peak this summer. We’ve seen prices come off the top by about 6% since this June.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a home seller, it’s a great time to list. Prices are still near all-time highs. If you’re a buyer, inventory is opening up and prices are down a bit. There’s a great window for you to come in and buy your dream home. Either way, the time to buy or sell is now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about the market or want to discuss your buying or selling plans further, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 17:06:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/has-silicon-valley-market-hit-its-peak.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/has-silicon-valley-market-hit-its-peak.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Updates</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>4 Qualities of an Exceptional Buying Agent</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/XUfz2CG9eqY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need a real estate representative for your next home purchase, there are four qualities to look for if you want to hire the best possible agent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
Considering Buying? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.siliconvalleyrealestatesearch.com/?utm_source=BLOG&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Video+Blog&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for gateway access to MLS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Considering Selling? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.siliconvalleyrealestatesearch.com/home-valuation/?utm_source=VYRAL&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Vyral+Emails+&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.siliconvalleyrealestatesearch.com/off-market-list/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to access off-site properties&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes time to buy a new home, how can you be sure that the agent you’ve hired is well-suited for the job?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are four key qualities to look for when evaluating an agent’s fitness for your transaction:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. How much experience does the agent have?&lt;/strong&gt; About 90% of the homes in our market are sold by about 10% of the active agents within it. What’s more is that the average agent only sells between three and five homes every year. A truly experienced agent will be much more active than this. Find someone who is not only very active, but is also providing quality service to their clients. Zillow is a great resource for finding active agents—they have profiles set up on the website, and clients can leave reviews for you to look at. You can even check out our Zillow profile by clicking &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zillow.com/profile/BrettJenningsTeam/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. On average, agents on our team typically sell between 18 and 30 homes a year—five times the number of the average agent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. What negotiation skills does the agent have?&lt;/strong&gt; Most brokerages provide contract training, but training on negotiation isn’t as typical. However, negotiation skills are extremely important, since it’s through negotiation that you can determine how much equity you’ll end up with at the end of your transaction. Everyone on our team is a certified negotiation expert, all taught with the same curriculum used at Harvard Law. We’re very effective in getting our clients homes for the lowest possible price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=EVERYONE ON OUR TEAM IS A CERTIFIED NEGOTIATION EXPERT, ALL TAUGHT WITH THE SAME CURRICULUM USED AT HARVARD LAW.%20http://localhost:4000/what-qualities-do-top-agents-have.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“EVERYONE ON OUR TEAM IS A CERTIFIED NEGOTIATION EXPERT, ALL TAUGHT WITH THE SAME CURRICULUM USED AT HARVARD LAW.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. What resources does the agent have?&lt;/strong&gt; A good buyer’s representative will offer you some off-market properties in addition to what can be found on the MLS. Almost 25% of the transactions that take place today involve homes that never made it the MLS. Those transactions are brokered between the top 10% of agents mentioned earlier. In addition to getting you access to more listings, a top agent can provide other resources like vendor referrals for movers, painters, contractors, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Can you click with their personality?&lt;/strong&gt; Over the course of the transaction, agents and clients tend to form an intimate relationship. We’re helping you build your dream of moving into your new home, so of course you’d want to work with someone you actually enjoyed working with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re in need of an agent to represent you during your next home purchase, we’d be delighted to interview for the opportunity to help you find your dream home, so feel free to reach out us. We’ll be right here, ready to help you create a better life through real estate.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 14:40:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-qualities-do-top-agents-have.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-qualities-do-top-agents-have.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dont Forget These Home Buying Costs</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/PH50JJ66b88?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When buying a home, it’s sometimes easy to forget about certain other costs that come with it. Here are five such costs that you need to remember to budget for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-cta&quot;&gt;
Considering Buying? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.siliconvalleyrealestatesearch.com/?utm_source=BLOG&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Video+Blog&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for gateway access to MLS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Considering Selling? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.siliconvalleyrealestatesearch.com/home-valuation/?utm_source=VYRAL&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Vyral+Emails+&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.siliconvalleyrealestatesearch.com/off-market-list/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Click here to access off-site properties&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a homebuyer, here are five costs that often get forgotten about that you need to remember to budget for:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. The down payment.&lt;/strong&gt; Most people don’t actually forget the down payment, but they forget about what kind of difference how much you put down makes. In our area, you can put down as little as 3% for any property up to $700,000. Above that price, you usually have to put down a minimum of 10%. To get the best interest rate from your lender, you’ll have to put down 20% or more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Your financial reserves.&lt;/strong&gt; You’ll need at least six months’ worth of mortgage payments and property tax payments saved up when you buy a home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Moving expenses.&lt;/strong&gt; Unless you’re doing it all yourself (which I don’t recommend), moving isn’t cheap. A good moving company usually costs between $2,500 and $4,000, and we can refer you to several movers who will take great care of you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=UNLESS YOU’RE DOING IT ALL YOURSELF, MOVING ISN’T CHEAP.%20http://localhost:4000/dont-forget-these-home-buying-costs.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“UNLESS YOU’RE DOING IT ALL YOURSELF, MOVING ISN’T CHEAP.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Furniture.&lt;/strong&gt; Buying a new home is exciting, and once you move in, odds are you’ll want to fix it up exactly the way you want it. This usually means buying new furniture. Also, don’t forget about the essential items you might need to buy, like a new broom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Home updates.&lt;/strong&gt; If your new home has an old bathroom that you want to fix up, you’ll have to budget for that. How much this will cost you can vary, so we’d be happy to come to your home, give you an estimate, and recommend some excellent contractors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any more questions about these costs or you have any other real estate needs, feel free to give me a call or shoot me an email. I’d be happy to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 11:10:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/dont-forget-these-home-buying-costs.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/dont-forget-these-home-buying-costs.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
