<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Silicon Valley Real Estate Podcast with Brett Jennings</title>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://localhost:4000"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Brett Jennings Real Estate Experts - your professional Silicon Valley Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Brett Jennings</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2019-05-23 13:45:46 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Brett Jennings</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Silicon Valley, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>Brett@TheRealExperts.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Brett Jennings</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Brett Jennings</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Silicon Valley, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Silicon Valley Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Brett Jennings Real Estate Experts - your professional Silicon Valley Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Sell Your Home Without a Realtor</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-sell-your-home-without-a-realtor.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Brett Jennings</author>
        <pubDate>2019-04-05 14:08:36 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/+Videos/2019/April/Real+Estate+Experts-+How+to+Sell+Your+Home+Without+a+Realtor.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Since we’re real estate professionals ourselves, you may be wondering why we’d want to tell you how to sell a home without us. Because we’re in such a hot market, plenty of people have been asking us how to sell a home on their own, so we figured we’d provide the information for doing so. Here are the five steps for selling your home without a Realtor:

1. Prepare your home for the market. Well-prepared homes are selling for 5% to 7% more than unprepared homes. Clean up your home, declutter, and paint rooms that you feel need it. Keep in mind that the money you put into preparing the property will often yield a 200% to 300% return when you sell.

2. Market your home. Zillow is one of the biggest online marketplaces for homes, and over 50% of buyers are going to this site when beginning their home search. Zillow will allow you to post your home for free, but you also want to take advantage of the multiple listing service (MLS). With a quick search online, you can find services that will list your home on the MLS without an agent.

3. Retain counsel for help with the paperwork. A good real estate attorney will help you with contracts and disclosures. There are a number of legally required disclosures in California, and if you miss any, you’re putting yourself at risk.

4. Have good negotiation skills. Once the offers come in on your home, you want to be able to negotiate with the buyers. If your negotiating skills aren’t so great, you can always lean on your real estate attorney to help out.

“One of the biggest things we do as professional Realtors is help you get more money for your sale.”

5. Get post-sale protection. Title insurance is often required when you take out a mortgage loan with your bank. We recommend you purchase a home warranty—if anything goes wrong in the year following the buyer’s purchase of your home, it’s covered by the warranty. Both of these minimize legal issues you may encounter down the road.

Following these steps will help you sell your home, but it may not sell for top dollar. One of the biggest things we do as professional Realtors is help you get more money for your sale. Here’s a funny story: The founder of ForSaleByOwner.com listed his home on his own site and related sites, but it went unsold for six months. After finding no luck through his own resources, he hired a Realtor and sold it for more than asking price. It just goes to show that a good Realtor can go a long way.

If you’re considering selling your home, let us demonstrate what we can do for you. We have a market-proven process that is guaranteed to get your home sold for more money—up to 18% more than the neighborhood average. Feel free to reach out to us if you’d like a consultation, have any questions, or need more information. We look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/+Videos/2019/April/Real+Estate+Experts-+How+to+Sell+Your+Home+Without+a+Realtor.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/+Videos/2019/April/Real+Estate+Experts-+How+to+Sell+Your+Home+Without+a+Realtor.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here are the five steps to take when selling your home without a Realtor.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Jennings</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here are the five steps to take when selling your home without a Realtor.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Silicon Valley, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>5 Ways to Make Your Home Shine</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/5-ways-to-make-your-home-shine.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Brett Jennings</author>
        <pubDate>2019-03-18 12:54:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/+Videos/2019/March/Real+Estate+Experts-+5+Ways+to+Make+Your+Home+Shine.mp4</guid>
        <description>

There are really five key things to think about when it comes to sprucing up your curb appeal:

1. Spruce up your landscaping. Go through the front of the property and trim back any bushes or trees that need pruning. Put some nice, fresh, colorful flowers in the flowerbeds, and then add mulch or bark to any areas of exposed dirt to create a nice, crisp line between any concrete or grass and the flowerbed. 

2. Pressure-wash the exterior of the home. If you don’t have a pressure washer, there is the option of renting one or else borrowing one from the Brett Jennings Real Estate Experts—we do allow clients and potential clients to use it, so feel free to ask.

“If you are repainting, you might also think about changing the color, since some colors might be more en vogue than what you currently have.”

3. Paint the exterior if necessary. It’s probably been a number of years since you’ve last painted your home, if you ever have at all. Consider repainting the exterior to give your home a crisp look. If you are repainting, you might also think about changing the color, since some colors might be more en vogue than what you currently have.

4. Update your home’s accents. Such accents include your shutters and exterior light fixtures like wall sconces. These are relatively inexpensive and easy to change out, and they can give your home an updated look.

5. Focus on the front door and garage door. We never get a second chance to make a first impression, and a nice front door and garage door can give your home an added pop.

Hopefully these tips will give you a better idea of how to make your home more attractive to both passersby and to potential buyers. If you have any more questions about maximizing your home’s curb appeal, we’d be happy to come take a look at your home and create a customized plan for you at no cost. Feel free to reach out to us. We hope to hear from you soon!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/+Videos/2019/March/Real+Estate+Experts-+5+Ways+to+Make+Your+Home+Shine.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/+Videos/2019/March/Real+Estate+Experts-+5+Ways+to+Make+Your+Home+Shine.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>How can you maximize the curb appeal of your home? Today I’ll give you a few tips.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Jennings</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>How can you maximize the curb appeal of your home? Today I’ll give you a few tips.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Silicon Valley, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Is Zillow’s Zestimate Feature Costing You Money?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/is-zillows-zestimate-feature-costing-you-money.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Brett Jennings</author>
        <pubDate>2019-02-25 16:37:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/+Videos/2019/February/Real+Estate+Experts-+Is+Zillows+Zestimate+Feature+Costing+You+Money_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

The big questions for today are: What is a Zestimate, how accurate is it, and how can you make sure that it’s not costing you money?

What is a Zestimate? Well, the Zestimate is just an automated valuation model that’s derived from an algorithm that incorporates basic, public information about your home and other homes in the area to come up with an estimated value.

Is the Zestimate accurate? Well, Zillow’s own website admits that the Zestimate can be anywhere from 10% to 20% off the market value of a home. It really only is meant to be a starting point. 

What affects the value of a Zestimate? The algorithm used to value a home is based on the specifics of your home, like your bed and bath count, the market trends in your area, or how much the aggregate value of your zip code has increased; and it also looks at recent or past sales. If you’ve sold your home recently for below market value, your home’s Zestimate will be a little undervalued until a certain amount of time has passed.

“If you want a more accurate estimate of your home’s value, I strongly advise you to enlist the help of a local Realtor to do a broker price opinion, or else to hire an appraiser.”

Because Zillow only uses basic information to calculate your Zestimate, there are certain things that the website can’t factor in, such as:


  Your home’s upgrades
  Distinct features of your home, like views, etc.
  Any additions you’ve made to the property


If you’re a homeowner, here’s what I suggest you do in order to insulate yourself:

Find your Zestimate online and claim your home. Zillow does allow you to audit the specifications of your home and add in certain features the site will have missed. However, the most important thing to do is to make sure your bed/bath count and your square footage of both your home and your lot are recorded accurately. At least then you’ll know that you’ll get Zillow’s best estimate.

If you want a more accurate estimate of your home’s value, I strongly advise you to enlist the help of a local Realtor to do a broker price opinion, or else to hire an appraiser.

In that case, give the Brett Jennings Group a call. We can do a free assessment of your property, and while we’re there, we can also give you some tips and ideas on what you can do to increase the value of your home with some simple upgrades and fix-ups before you bring it to market.

If you’d like more details on increasing your home’s value, check out one of our other video blogs called “5 Tips to Boost Your Home’s Value.” It is one of our most popular blogs. We hope to hear from you soon!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/+Videos/2019/February/Real+Estate+Experts-+Is+Zillows+Zestimate+Feature+Costing+You+Money_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/+Videos/2019/February/Real+Estate+Experts-+Is+Zillows+Zestimate+Feature+Costing+You+Money_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>By now, you’ve probably heard of Zillow’s Zestimate feature—but is it costing you money? Today I’ll discuss.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Jennings</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>By now, you’ve probably heard of Zillow’s Zestimate feature—but is it costing you money? Today I’ll discuss.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Silicon Valley, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Power of Partnership</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/power-of-partnership.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Brett Jennings</author>
        <pubDate>2019-01-31 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>






I’m very happy to announce that myself and Olympia Pistalu are combining our businesses into one operation, where we’ll bring equal parts enthusiasm and professionalism to better serve your needs this year and beyond!

If you’re unfamiliar with Olympia and her career accomplishments, I’d like to give a brief introduction: She launched in 2016, and in her first year with Coldwell Banker, she earned the designation of Rookie of the Year. She circled around my world this year, and with the 10 years of experience we bring, there’s added value in us working together.

“With the 10 years of experience we bring, there’s added value in us working together.”

Olympia cites her confidence that our systems and processes will facilitate her ability to enhance her clients’ experiences and our clients’ experiences overall as a key reason she decided to join the team.

To that end, the two of us want to be a great resource for you, as it relates to real estate. Therefore, we’ll be reaching out to you on a regular basis with some of the most relevant information from today’s market.

If you’re thinking about selling your home or you’re curious about your home’s value, click on the “home value” tab. This will give you an instant value of your home. And if you’re considering buying, click on the “home search” tab. This will give you access to all homes for sale in Silicon Valley.

If you have questions or for help with any and all of your real estate needs, feel free to reach out to Olympia and the rest of our team. We look forward to serving you in 2019!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>We’ve combined forces with Olympia Pistalu to make your real estate experience more prosperous and fulfilling in 2019 and beyond. Meet Olympia in today’s message.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Jennings</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>We’ve combined forces with Olympia Pistalu to make your real estate experience more prosperous and fulfilling in 2019 and beyond. Meet Olympia in today’s message.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Silicon Valley, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>4 Tips to Help You Hire the Right Listing Agent</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/4-tips-to-help-you-hire-the-right-listing-agent.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Brett Jennings</author>
        <pubDate>2019-01-08 14:16:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/Videos/2019/January/Brett+Jennings+Real+Estate+Experts-+4+Tips+to+Help+You+Hire+the+Right+Listing+Agent.mp4</guid>
        <description>

How can you find the right agent when selling your home? There are four key criteria that you should look out for:

1. How much experience do they have? Did you know that 90% of home sales are done by 10% of the available real estate agents? Fortunately in today’s market, we do have an online resource that provides transparency to consumers: Zillow. You can see how many home sales an agent has done, figure out who’s doing business by looking at their activity, and find out what it’s like to work with an agent by reading their reviews. From there, pick two to three agents to interview.

2. What are their specific skills and training? Selling a home is a lot different than buying a home and requires a completely different skill set. You should also make sure that your agent has experience in home improvement. Homes that are prepared and updated for the market are selling for 5% to 7% more money than homes that aren’t. An agent with home improvement experience can tell you where to put money into your house in order to get the most money possible out of your home sale.

“90% of home sales are made by 10% of real estate agents.”

Online marketing skills are also incredibly important. These days, 98% of buyers start their home search online. The price your home sells for is a function of how many people see it online and how many of those come to see it in person.

Finally, make sure your agent has great negotiation skills. Have they been trained in negotiation? Our agents are all certified negotiators. We also have one of the most innovative real estate teams in the country when it comes to online marketing, and about 75% of our clients have us help them during home renovations.

3. Does the agent have deep resources? Preparing a home for sale can be a big job. You may need to get carpeting cleaned or replaced, update the kitchen, or take care of other home improvements. You need to hire someone with a team of resources to take a lot of that work off your plate. Hire someone who can put you in touch with a great mover as well.

4. Hire someone you feel comfortable with. Selling a home can be stressful. Selling also takes longer than buying a home. Buying a home usually takes about 30 days. Selling can be a 90-day process, so hire an agent that has a great personality. It’s important that you feel comfortable working with this agent for the next two to three months.

We are happy to help you with any other home selling questions you may have. Just give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/Videos/2019/January/Brett+Jennings+Real+Estate+Experts-+4+Tips+to+Help+You+Hire+the+Right+Listing+Agent.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/Videos/2019/January/Brett+Jennings+Real+Estate+Experts-+4+Tips+to+Help+You+Hire+the+Right+Listing+Agent.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>How can you make sure that you hire the best real estate agent for your home sale? I’ll go over four criteria you should look for when interviewing agents.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Jennings</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>How can you make sure that you hire the best real estate agent for your home sale? I’ll go over four criteria you should look for when interviewing agents.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Silicon Valley, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>8 Ways to Increase Your Home’s Value on a Budget</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/8-ways-to-increase-your-homes-value-on-a-budget.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Brett Jennings</author>
        <pubDate>2018-11-05 14:28:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/Videos/2018/November/Brett+Jennings+Real+Estate+Experts-+8+Ways+to+Increase+Your+Homes+Value+on+a+Budget.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Maximizing your home’s value doesn’t have to cost an arm and a leg. There are eight different ways that you can add up to $50,000 to your home’s value by spending less than $6,000:

1. Deep clean your home. Hire a cleaner that’s going to get all the grease off of your range hood, dust in the areas that you haven’t seen for a while, and get the house looking immaculate. This will make the home feel inviting and give buyers a great first impression.

2. Declutter the home. Put away anything that’s smaller than a football that sits on your shelf. Any old, clunky furniture should go in the garage as well. It’s all about maximizing and showcasing the space you have.

3. Paint. You don’t need to paint every square inch of every room—you might just need some touch-ups here and there. Make sure everything is in a neutral color.

4. Update any fixtures or appliances. This includes doorknobs, hinges, and switches. These are relatively low-cost updates, but they bring a lot of value to your property. You could spend as little as $500 but add thousands in value.

“A home inspection will make sure that no problems are overlooked.”

5. Update the landscaping. Trim back overgrown bushes, put down some fresh mulch, and plant some new flowers.

6. Small bathroom updates. If you have an older bathroom with an older light fixture or vanity, you can get a brand new one for $500 or $600 that will completely update the look of the room.

7. Clean the carpets. We work with a few different carpet cleaners that do amazing work and can restore your carpets to just like new. This will probably cost a few hundred bucks.

8. Have a home inspection. There are problems that we can’t see just from looking at the home, but we want to address and fix anything that’s wrong before we get it listed. A home inspection will cost around $750, but it will also help address any deferred maintenance and take any surprises out of the equation.

If you have any questions about this list or if you want more tips on how to get your home ready for sale, please feel free to give us a call or send us an email any time. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/Videos/2018/November/Brett+Jennings+Real+Estate+Experts-+8+Ways+to+Increase+Your+Homes+Value+on+a+Budget.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/Videos/2018/November/Brett+Jennings+Real+Estate+Experts-+8+Ways+to+Increase+Your+Homes+Value+on+a+Budget.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>You can maximize the value of your home when it comes time to sell without spending too much money. Here are eight of our best budget-friendly tips.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Jennings</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>You can maximize the value of your home when it comes time to sell without spending too much money. Here are eight of our best budget-friendly tips.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Silicon Valley, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Can Facebook Help You Sell Your Home?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/can-facebook-help-you-sell-your-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Brett Jennings</author>
        <pubDate>2018-10-15 18:26:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/Videos/2018/October/Brett+Jennings+Real+Estate+Experts-+Can+Facebook+Help+You+Sell+Your+Home%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>
If used correctly, Facebook can be an amazing marketing tool for today’s home sellers.


Considering Buying? Click here for gateway access to MLS
Considering Selling? Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation
Click here to access off-site properties


In the age of the internet, there are many online resources that can help people sell their homes—but what about Facebook? Can Facebook help you sell?

Actually, yes. Using a targeted approach, Facebook can allow sellers to double their exposure online.

Here’s how it works:

First, ask yourself who the ideal buyer for your property is. Defining the profile of your ideal buyer will help you determine what your “avatar” is and how you can market to them. In this case, the term  “avatar” means your target buyer.

Once you have this avatar in mind, it’s time to film and post video footage of your home. Videos get the highest level of engagement on Facebook, and are also the most highly prioritized in terms of where they appear on the site.

“USING A TARGETED APPROACH, FACEBOOK CAN ALLOW SELLERS TO DOUBLE THEIR EXPOSURE ONLINE.”

The third step in leveraging this platform to gain exposure for your listing is to pay for Facebook ads. Using Facebook advertising to reach your specific, ideal buyer can vastly increase the amount of attention your listing receives.

Facebook is such an effective real estate marketing tool that our team was recently interviewed by The Wall Street Journal regarding this tactic. You can see the full article here, but to summarize what we revealed during the interview, our team was once able to sell a client’s home for $125,000 more than the next-highest offer by using Facebook in our marketing.

The bottom line is this: Using Facebook as a tool to help sell your home can be massively effective.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/Videos/2018/October/Brett+Jennings+Real+Estate+Experts-+Can+Facebook+Help+You+Sell+Your+Home%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/Videos/2018/October/Brett+Jennings+Real+Estate+Experts-+Can+Facebook+Help+You+Sell+Your+Home%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>
If used correctly, Facebook can be an amazing marketing tool for today’s home sellers.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Jennings</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>
If used correctly, Facebook can be an amazing marketing tool for today’s home sellers.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Silicon Valley, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Has The Silicon Valley Market Hit Its Peak?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/has-silicon-valley-market-hit-its-peak.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Updates</category>
        
        <author>Brett Jennings</author>
        <pubDate>2018-10-01 17:06:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/Videos/2018/October/Brett+Jennings+Real+Estate+Experts-+Has+The+Silicon+Valley+Market+Hit+Its+Peak%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

A lot of people have been wondering if the Silicon Valley real estate market has peaked. Today we’re taking a closer look to determine whether that’s the case or not.


Considering Buying? Click here for gateway access to MLS
Considering Selling? Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation
Click here to access off-site properties


With Silicon Valley home prices up by 25% this year already, many area property owners are wondering whether prices can go higher or the market has hit its peak. I’ve got a fall market update for you today that will answer that question.

To understand where this market is headed, we have to understand what’s been driving it up in the first place. Real estate is a supply-and-demand driven market, but there is an affordability ceiling.

For most real estate markets around the country, a balanced inventory means we have about six months of supply. This means that if no other homes came on the market, all the available homes would be bought in six months. Right now in Silicon Valley, we have only six weeks of inventory available, which is actually up 50% year over year.

What’s keeping our inventory constrained? A few different things. First, retirees aren’t moving. In fact, 87% of retirees are staying in their current homes as opposed to relocating or downsizing. Another factor is move-up buyers. Buyers who purchased their home five to 10 years ago and want to purchase a larger home now are facing the prospect of a property tax bill that is double or triple what they’re currently paying. For that reason, these would-be sellers are deciding to remodel or expand instead. Lastly, anyone who has bought a house in the last five years likely has a very low interest rate. If they decide to buy, they will see their interest rate increase almost by 50%. Many are choosing to remodel or expand their current properties, instead.

“HOME PRICES ARE RISING FASTER THAN WAGES ARE.”

What drives demand in real estate? Jobs. In Silicon Valley, there are plenty of them. Last year, 47,000 new jobs were created and 22,000 people moved here. The real issue is that only 12,000 new housing permits were issued, mostly for condos and apartments. As you can see, we have a low supply and high demand, which has driven the market higher. You would think there would be no end in sight, but buyers can only stretch so far, which goes back to the affordability ceiling I discussed earlier.

As higher and higher paid workers chase higher and higher priced homes, we get to a point where house prices are going up faster than wages. No matter where you work, you probably didn’t get a 25% raise this year to keep pace with home prices.

59% of tech workers surveyed said they couldn’t afford the house they live in with today’s prices and interest rates. Only 34% of first-time buyers entering this market can afford to buy a home right now. This means that our market hit its peak this summer. We’ve seen prices come off the top by about 6% since this June.

If you’re a home seller, it’s a great time to list. Prices are still near all-time highs. If you’re a buyer, inventory is opening up and prices are down a bit. There’s a great window for you to come in and buy your dream home. Either way, the time to buy or sell is now.

If you have any questions about the market or want to discuss your buying or selling plans further, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/Videos/2018/October/Brett+Jennings+Real+Estate+Experts-+Has+The+Silicon+Valley+Market+Hit+Its+Peak%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/Videos/2018/October/Brett+Jennings+Real+Estate+Experts-+Has+The+Silicon+Valley+Market+Hit+Its+Peak%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

A lot of people have been wondering if the Silicon Valley real estate market has peaked. Today we’re taking a closer look to determine whether that’s the case or not.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Jennings</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

A lot of people have been wondering if the Silicon Valley real estate market has peaked. Today we’re taking a closer look to determine whether that’s the case or not.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Silicon Valley, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>4 Qualities of an Exceptional Buying Agent</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-qualities-do-top-agents-have.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Brett Jennings</author>
        <pubDate>2018-09-07 14:40:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/Videos/2018/September/Brett+Jennings+Real+Estate+Experts-+What+Qualities+Do+Top+Agents+Have%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you need a real estate representative for your next home purchase, there are four qualities to look for if you want to hire the best possible agent.


Considering Buying? Click here for gateway access to MLS
Considering Selling? Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation
Click here to access off-site properties


When it comes time to buy a new home, how can you be sure that the agent you’ve hired is well-suited for the job?

There are four key qualities to look for when evaluating an agent’s fitness for your transaction:

1. How much experience does the agent have? About 90% of the homes in our market are sold by about 10% of the active agents within it. What’s more is that the average agent only sells between three and five homes every year. A truly experienced agent will be much more active than this. Find someone who is not only very active, but is also providing quality service to their clients. Zillow is a great resource for finding active agents—they have profiles set up on the website, and clients can leave reviews for you to look at. You can even check out our Zillow profile by clicking here. On average, agents on our team typically sell between 18 and 30 homes a year—five times the number of the average agent.

2. What negotiation skills does the agent have? Most brokerages provide contract training, but training on negotiation isn’t as typical. However, negotiation skills are extremely important, since it’s through negotiation that you can determine how much equity you’ll end up with at the end of your transaction. Everyone on our team is a certified negotiation expert, all taught with the same curriculum used at Harvard Law. We’re very effective in getting our clients homes for the lowest possible price.

“EVERYONE ON OUR TEAM IS A CERTIFIED NEGOTIATION EXPERT, ALL TAUGHT WITH THE SAME CURRICULUM USED AT HARVARD LAW.”

3. What resources does the agent have? A good buyer’s representative will offer you some off-market properties in addition to what can be found on the MLS. Almost 25% of the transactions that take place today involve homes that never made it the MLS. Those transactions are brokered between the top 10% of agents mentioned earlier. In addition to getting you access to more listings, a top agent can provide other resources like vendor referrals for movers, painters, contractors, and more.

4. Can you click with their personality? Over the course of the transaction, agents and clients tend to form an intimate relationship. We’re helping you build your dream of moving into your new home, so of course you’d want to work with someone you actually enjoyed working with.

If you’re in need of an agent to represent you during your next home purchase, we’d be delighted to interview for the opportunity to help you find your dream home, so feel free to reach out us. We’ll be right here, ready to help you create a better life through real estate.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/Videos/2018/September/Brett+Jennings+Real+Estate+Experts-+What+Qualities+Do+Top+Agents+Have%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/Videos/2018/September/Brett+Jennings+Real+Estate+Experts-+What+Qualities+Do+Top+Agents+Have%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

If you need a real estate representative for your next home purchase, there are four qualities to look for if you want to hire the best possible agent.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Jennings</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

If you need a real estate representative for your next home purchase, there are four qualities to look for if you want to hire the best possible agent.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Silicon Valley, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Dont Forget These Home Buying Costs</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/dont-forget-these-home-buying-costs.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Brett Jennings</author>
        <pubDate>2018-08-20 11:10:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/+Videos/2018/Brett+Jennings+Real+Estate+Experts-+Dont+Forget+These+Home+Buying+Costs.mp4</guid>
        <description>

When buying a home, it’s sometimes easy to forget about certain other costs that come with it. Here are five such costs that you need to remember to budget for.


Considering Buying? Click here for gateway access to MLS
Considering Selling? Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation
Click here to access off-site properties


As a homebuyer, here are five costs that often get forgotten about that you need to remember to budget for:

1. The down payment. Most people don’t actually forget the down payment, but they forget about what kind of difference how much you put down makes. In our area, you can put down as little as 3% for any property up to $700,000. Above that price, you usually have to put down a minimum of 10%. To get the best interest rate from your lender, you’ll have to put down 20% or more.

2. Your financial reserves. You’ll need at least six months’ worth of mortgage payments and property tax payments saved up when you buy a home.

3. Moving expenses. Unless you’re doing it all yourself (which I don’t recommend), moving isn’t cheap. A good moving company usually costs between $2,500 and $4,000, and we can refer you to several movers who will take great care of you.

“UNLESS YOU’RE DOING IT ALL YOURSELF, MOVING ISN’T CHEAP.”

4. Furniture. Buying a new home is exciting, and once you move in, odds are you’ll want to fix it up exactly the way you want it. This usually means buying new furniture. Also, don’t forget about the essential items you might need to buy, like a new broom.

5. Home updates. If your new home has an old bathroom that you want to fix up, you’ll have to budget for that. How much this will cost you can vary, so we’d be happy to come to your home, give you an estimate, and recommend some excellent contractors.

If you have any more questions about these costs or you have any other real estate needs, feel free to give me a call or shoot me an email. I’d be happy to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/+Videos/2018/Brett+Jennings+Real+Estate+Experts-+Dont+Forget+These+Home+Buying+Costs.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/+Videos/2018/Brett+Jennings+Real+Estate+Experts-+Dont+Forget+These+Home+Buying+Costs.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

When buying a home, it’s sometimes easy to forget about certain other costs that come with it. Here are five such costs that you need to remember to budget for.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Jennings</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

When buying a home, it’s sometimes easy to forget about certain other costs that come with it. Here are five such costs that you need to remember to budget for.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Silicon Valley, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Sell Your Home for 18% More Money Part 5: Negotiations</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-sell-your-home-for-18-more-money.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Brett Jennings</author>
        <pubDate>2018-08-06 10:31:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/+Videos/2018/Brett+Jennings+Real+Estate+Experts-+How+to+Sell+Your+Home+for+18%2525+More+Money+Part+5-+Negotiations.mp4</guid>
        <description>

In today’s fifth and final installment into our latest series, we’ll be discussing the last component of earning more money for your home: Negotiations.


Considering Buying? Click here for gateway access to MLS
Considering Selling? Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation
Click here to access off-site properties


“HAVING A SKILLED NEGOTIATOR WHO CAN THINK OUTSIDE THE BOX WILL BE VERY HELPFUL FOR YOU IN ANY REAL ESTATE SCENARIO.”

There are four strategies that I recommend all sellers employ when it comes time to negotiate a deal for their home sale. These strategies are the last piece of the puzzle in earning 18% more for your property when it comes time to sell.

1. Encourage preemptive offers. This strategy entails capturing interested buyers before your home technically hits the multiple listing service by marketing it as “coming soon.” Typically, it’s advisable to put a list price that’s higher than your expectation at this point in the process. I can tell you from experience that because of our low inventory, buyers are tired of getting beaten out and will be willing submit a preemptive offer that is at or above your price expectation when you follow this strategy.

2. Price for multiple offers. If you didn’t earn the price you’d hoped for during the “coming soon” phase of your listing process, it’s time to price your home in a way that represents a great value and encourages multiple offers. When buyers see your listing as an exceptional deal, they will be more likely to compete over it. This will ultimately drive up the price and help you net more for your home.

3. Determine your best alternative to a negotiated agreement (BATNA). More simply put, this strategy essentially serves as the “Plan B” you should fall onto in the event that your original negotiated agreement is somehow compromised. This will ensure that if anything unexpected happens during the course of the deal, you will still have an idea of how you’d like to proceed.

4. Be creative. If you’re close to getting the results you want but just aren’t there yet, you should consult with your agent about possible solutions. As an example, we had a seller recently whose minimum bottom line for their home was $1 million, but whose buyer had a loan approval that was maxed out at $990,000. To compensate for this $10,000 disparity, we advised the seller to credit the buyer with $5,000, with the understanding that the credit was to be explicitly dedicated toward lowering the buyer’s interest rate on their loan. The buyer was able to lower their interest rate from 4.25% to 4%, which raised their mortgage approval up to just over $1 million. As a result, the buyer was able to secure the home and the seller was able to net their desired price. Having a skilled negotiator who can think outside the box will be very helpful for you in any real estate scenario.

Ultimately, the bottom line is that doing many little things right throughout a transaction can make a big difference in your success.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/+Videos/2018/Brett+Jennings+Real+Estate+Experts-+How+to+Sell+Your+Home+for+18%2525+More+Money+Part+5-+Negotiations.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/+Videos/2018/Brett+Jennings+Real+Estate+Experts-+How+to+Sell+Your+Home+for+18%2525+More+Money+Part+5-+Negotiations.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

In today’s fifth and final installment into our latest series, we’ll be discussing the last component of earning more money for your home: Negotiations.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Jennings</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

In today’s fifth and final installment into our latest series, we’ll be discussing the last component of earning more money for your home: Negotiations.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Silicon Valley, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Win a Multiple Offer Situation: Part 1</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-win-multiple-offer-situation.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Brett Jennings</author>
        <pubDate>2018-07-12 16:47:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/+Videos/2018/Brett+Jennings+Real+Estate+Experts-+Competitive+Offers.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Having the right financing is essential to winning a multiple offer situation, and today we’ll discuss three pieces of advice related to this point.


Considering Buying? Click here for gateway access to MLS
Considering Selling? Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation
Click here to access off-site properties


Today’s market is extremely competitive for buyers. So when they’re up against multiple bids from other buyers on the same house, what can they do to make their offer stand out? Today’s topic marks the first installment of my series that addresses that very conundrum.

Our team’s preferred lender, Michael Treon, is going to help me cover the answer to this. Let’s kick off our discussion with three things buyers should do to set themselves up for success.

1. Get fully approved. Winning in a multiple offer situation starts with getting the right financing in place. Getting fully approved and underwritten, not just pre-approved, is essential. A full approval will allow you to be competitive in the marketplace because it eliminates the need for you to include a loan contingency on your offers. Today’s sellers are looking for the cleanest possible offers because they want to close quickly and without issue.

“WINNING IN A MULTIPLE OFFER SITUATION STARTS WITH GETTING THE RIGHT FINANCING IN PLACE.”

2. Select a lender who can provide financing the performs like cash in the market. Over 30% of buyers in today’s market are submitting all-cash offers. These offers easily win out against those with conventional loan financing because they allow a shorter close of escrow. Therefore, it’s very important that the offer you submit can stack up against ones such as this. Michael Treon and his team are able to provide buyers with financing that allows for an exceptionally fast close of just 17 days.

3. Consider all loan options. Don’t limit yourself by looking exclusively at 30-year fixed mortgages. The reality is that most homeowners won’t stay in a property for the full 30 years, so it’s critical to consider alternative loan options. There are a lot of opportunities to secure a home with a loan product that makes sense for your personal circumstances.

Now that you understand how the right financing can boost your success in multiple offer situations, be on the lookout for part two of our series. Next time, we’ll talk about how to access off-market properties, and how doing so can help you find a home in today’s competitive market.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.

To view Michael Treon’s mortgage pre-approval process, click here.


Michael Treon, Senior Mortgage Loan Officer
PNC Bank | NMLS ID: 339550
michael.treon@pnc.com | pncmortgage.com/michaeltreon
(Office) 415.505.7558 | (f) 844.274.9911
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/+Videos/2018/Brett+Jennings+Real+Estate+Experts-+Competitive+Offers.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/+Videos/2018/Brett+Jennings+Real+Estate+Experts-+Competitive+Offers.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Having the right financing is essential to winning a multiple offer situation, and today we’ll discuss three pieces of advice related to this point.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Jennings</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Having the right financing is essential to winning a multiple offer situation, and today we’ll discuss three pieces of advice related to this point.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Silicon Valley, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Another Way to Net Up to 18% More for Your Home</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/another-way-to-earn-more-for-your.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Selling Tips</category>
        
        <author>Brett Jennings</author>
        <pubDate>2018-07-09 12:01:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/+Videos/2018/Brett+Jennings+Real+Estate+Experts-+Sell+for+more+part+4.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Marketing is a key step to net up to 18% more for your home. Today I’d like to go over four areas of marketing you must focus on to optimize your results.


Considering Buying? Click here for gateway access to MLS
Considering Selling? Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation
Click here to access off-site properties


Today I’m back with the fourth installment into our series on how you can sell your home for 18% more money. I know this sounds like a bold claim, but it’s true.

In previous episodes we talked about preparing, presenting, and pricing your home. This time we’ll be talking about the importance of marketing.

Marketing controls how many people see the home, both online and in person, and this exposure is what will dictate what the property sells for. To achieve optimal results, there are four main areas of marketing you must focus on:

1. Local marketing. This involves placing your property on the local MLS, which is syndicated to over 200 different websites.

“MARKETING CONTROLS HOW MANY PEOPLE SEE THE HOME, BOTH ONLINE AND IN PERSON, AND THIS EXPOSURE IS WHAT WILL DICTATE WHAT THE PROPERTY SELLS FOR.”

2. National marketing. Silicon Valley is a major relocation destination, so marketing your listing across the country could help you capture an out-of-state buyer. Websites like Zillow, Trulia, and Realtor.com will be some of your best resources in gaining national exposure. Our team allocates a lot of our marketing expenses into making sure our clients’ listings appear at the top of online searches.

3. International marketing. 31% of all property purchases in our state are either foreign or foreign-born. Therefore, it’s important not to miss out on this segment of the market. Our team has partnered with Proxio, a platform that allows us to connect and engage with over 100 different countries using 82 different websites.

4. Social media marketing. The internet is an incredible tool. In fact, Facebook could bring you nearly twice the exposure you’d get on Zillow.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/+Videos/2018/Brett+Jennings+Real+Estate+Experts-+Sell+for+more+part+4.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/+Videos/2018/Brett+Jennings+Real+Estate+Experts-+Sell+for+more+part+4.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Marketing is a key step to net up to 18% more for your home. Today I’d like to go over four areas of marketing you must focus on to optimize your results.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Jennings</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Marketing is a key step to net up to 18% more for your home. Today I’d like to go over four areas of marketing you must focus on to optimize your results.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Silicon Valley, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Move Up In a Tight Housing Market</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-make-move-up-in-our-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Brett Jennings</author>
        <pubDate>2018-04-10 13:50:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/+Videos/2018/Los+Gatos+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+Make+a+Move+Up+in+Our+Market.mp4</guid>
        <description>

How can we help move-up buyers in today’s market? Here are a few solutions.


Considering Buying? Click here for gateway access to MLS
Considering Selling? Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation
Click here to access off-site properties


The question that we’ve been hearing the most lately in our market is, “How do I make a move up in a low-inventory market like this?”

Most people would prefer to buy a home before selling, but most people can’t afford two mortgages at once. That puts the seller in a position where they need to sell first, but they aren’t comfortable selling with what’s out there for them to buy.

Our friend Shane Valente of Kal Financial is here today to talk about two major things that he can help you accomplish if you have a similar dilemma. These scenarios will allow you to get into a home without having to sell first.

One option is using the current equity for your home as a down payment through bridge financing. This way, you won’t have to qualify for two mortgages. You’ll be able to buy your new home first, then sell.

“WE HAVE A LIST OF OVER 300 OFF-MARKET PROPERTIES THAT AREN’T ON THE MLS.”

There’s one problem solved. Now, what should homebuyers do about the lack of inventory on the market? There are currently only 700 homes on the market in Santa Clara County. This is the lowest level of inventory we’ve seen in 14 years.

We’ve been diligently working to address this problem and we’ve been building a list of off-market properties, working with builders, flippers, and other agents to fill it up. This list currently has over 300 homes on it that don’t appear on the MLS or other online searches. If you find a property that’s not on the MLS, you can avoid having to participate in a bidding war.

If you’d like to learn more about bridge financing and how it can help you, give Shane a call at (408) 320-0876. If you have any other questions for our team or want to learn more about how we can help you accomplish your real estate goals, don’t hesitate to reach out and give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/+Videos/2018/Los+Gatos+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+Make+a+Move+Up+in+Our+Market.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/+Videos/2018/Los+Gatos+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+Make+a+Move+Up+in+Our+Market.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

How can we help move-up buyers in today’s market? Here are a few solutions.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Jennings</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

How can we help move-up buyers in today’s market? Here are a few solutions.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Silicon Valley, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How a Pre-Appraisal Can Net You Up To 8% More When Selling</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/selling-your-home-for-up-to-18-more-part3.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Brett Jennings</author>
        <pubDate>2018-03-21 11:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/+Videos/2018/Los+Gatos+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+sell+for+more+part+3.mp4</guid>
        <description>

We can sell your home for up to 18% more money. We’ll prove it to you.


Considering Buying? Click here for gateway access to MLS
Considering Selling? Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation
Click here to access off-site properties


How can you sell your home for up to 18% more money? It sounds like a bold claim, but I’ll prove to you that we can do it for you by walking you through the third part of our five-part process.

Last time, we talked about presenting your home to market and how we showcase your home using photo, video, and other cool technologies like Matterport. Once the home has been prepared and we’ve presented it to market, it’s now all about pricing.

Pricing is as much of an art as it is a science, and its extremely critical when it comes to getting the most money when selling your home. One of the strategies we like to use here at Brett Jennings Real Estate Experts is getting an appraisal done on the property. We find that if we use a professional appraiser, we can give that appraiser quote guidance to get us the most favorable value for your home. We can also use that appraisal to influence buyers to pay top dollar for your home. Here’s how that works.

For example, take the home we sold at Mountain View (pictured at 1:24 in the video). We first asked the local experts in the neighborhood who’d sold more homes in that particular zip code what they thought the value of this property would sell for when we brought it to market.

The agent said that it was worth about $1.35 million. We then got our appraiser to give us a generous appraisal on the property, which came in at about $1.42 million. After that, we priced the property at around $1.299 million less than the agent’s survey.

“PRICING IS AS MUCH OF AN ART AS IT IS A SCIENCE.”

Then, we included a copy of the appraisal in the disclosure package and on the agent comments on the MLS. We set a deadline of 10 days, because one weekend might not be enough to maximize the exposure for buyers. Also, by setting a deadline, we effectively forced buyers to compete. We ended up with seven offers, ranging from about $1.35 million up to $1.43 million, which was $10,000 over our appraised value.

We negotiated the top two offers against one another, eventually getting them up to $1.465 million. We actually got $115,000, or 8% more, in the sale of this home by using an appraisal strategically.

The reason that this works is that when buyers are faced with competition in a low-inventory market like ours, they’ll ask their agents what they need to offer in order to get the house. The agent, in most instances, has a printout from the MLS showing home values in that neighborhood; it could be a $150,000 swing in our favor. It really becomes a conversation about what the buyers are comfortable offering.

We found by having a pre-appraisal in our disclosure package, the agent is also going to reference the appraisal when consulting the buyers, advising them to offer at least the appraised value. Doing just that, we’ve gotten as much as 8% more than the average market value.

If you have any questions about pricing, using an appraisal strategically, or selling your home, feel free to reach out to me. I’d love to tell you more about our winning strategy.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/+Videos/2018/Los+Gatos+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+sell+for+more+part+3.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/+Videos/2018/Los+Gatos+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+sell+for+more+part+3.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

We can sell your home for up to 18% more money. We’ll prove it to you.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Jennings</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

We can sell your home for up to 18% more money. We’ll prove it to you.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Silicon Valley, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Selling Your Home For Up To 18% More - Part 2 - Presentation</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/selling-your-home-for-up-to-18-more-part2.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Brett Jennings</author>
        <pubDate>2018-01-12 16:14:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/+Videos/2018/Los+Gatos+Real+Estate+Agent-+We+Can+Sell+Your+Home+For+More+MoneyHeres+How.mp4</guid>
        <description>

We can sell your home for up to 18% more money. We’ll prove it to you. To watch the FULL VERSION of my presentation, CLICK HERE.


Considering Buying? Click here for gateway access to MLS
Considering Selling? Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation
Click here to access off-site properties


Welcome back to part two of my series about how to sell your home for up to 18% more money. I know that sounds like a bold claim, but we’ll prove it’s possible by walking you through our process.

Last time, we talked about preparing the home for sale. Once it’s prepared, it’s now about presenting your home to the market. How do we do that?

“BY USING THESE TECHNIQUES TO PRESENT YOUR HOME TO MARKET, WE CAN GET 200% TO 300% MORE BUYERS TO SEE YOUR HOME, WHICH ULTIMATELY DRIVES UP THE PRICE.”

The first thing to do is stage the home. If you have nice furniture, we might leave most or all of it in the home to show. Otherwise, we’ll bring in furniture that will showcase the home to look amazing online. We know that how your home shows online is the new curb appeal, that staged homes will sell for 2% to 3% more money, and that 95% of staged homes will sell within 14 days.

Secondly, once we’ve staged the home, we want to capture it in photo and video. Specifically, we want to use twilight photography to showcase your home. Why? Well, our marketing statistics show that photographing in twilight will not only make the home show well in nice lighting, but also that most other homes online aren’t doing twilight photography. We found that we get 200% to 300% more clicks using twilight photos than daylight photos. Ultimately, the price you get for your home is going to be a function of how many people see it online and click through the photos. That will determine how many offers you get down the road.

You also want to capture your home on video, which provides a perspective that still photos can’t provide. Video is the most frequently used medium with consumers on mobile devices. 70% of people are watching videos on their phones.

In addition, video enables us to nearly double your exposure by getting into one of the best marketing mediums—Facebook. We get thousands, if not tens of thousands, of views of our Facebook videos.

Finally, the last thing we do is capture the home using a technology called Matterport. This is effectively like a Google Streetview for you home, and you can view anywhere in and around the home, looking both up and down. Viewers can get a sense of what it’s like to be inside that home. It’s the next best thing to being there.

With Matterport’s newest technology, they even incorporate virtual reality. If someone has Oculus Rift or Google Cardboard, they can take their iPhone and see the home in 3-D as if they were walking through it.

By using these techniques to present your home to market, we can get 200% to 300% more buyers to see your home, which ultimately drives up the price.

If you have any questions about this or other real estate topics, feel free to give me a call. We’ll be right here, ready to help you create a better life through real estate.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/+Videos/2018/Los+Gatos+Real+Estate+Agent-+We+Can+Sell+Your+Home+For+More+MoneyHeres+How.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/+Videos/2018/Los+Gatos+Real+Estate+Agent-+We+Can+Sell+Your+Home+For+More+MoneyHeres+How.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

We can sell your home for up to 18% more money. We’ll prove it to you. To watch the FULL VERSION of my presentation, CLICK HERE.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Jennings</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

We can sell your home for up to 18% more money. We’ll prove it to you. To watch the FULL VERSION of my presentation, CLICK HERE.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Silicon Valley, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Selling Your Home For Up To 18% More - Part 1 - Preparation</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/selling-your-home-for-up-to-18-more-part1.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Brett Jennings</author>
        <pubDate>2017-09-27 08:47:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/Videos/2017/Los+Gatos+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+To+Sell+Your+Home+For+More+Money+%2528Part+1%2529.mp4</guid>
        <description>

How are we able to consistently sell homes for up to 18% over the market average? Here are the first two steps.

Watch This Next: 5 home improvements to boost your home’s value


Considering Buying? Click here for gateway access to MLS
Considering Selling? Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation
Click here to access off-site properties


How can we sell your home for 18% more money on average? I know it sounds like a bold claim, but over the next few videos I’ll walk you through the process to show you exactly how we do it.

This process was developed between 2011 and 2013 when I worked with an investor client to buy, sell, and remodel over 150 homes. The investor wanted every last drop of equity out of his homes, so it was my job to look at all the houses and find all those little details that could affect the final sale price of the home. This experience led me to develop this time tested and proven system. There are five main areas we focus on. Today we’re covering the first vital step.

“THERE ARE FIVE MAIN AREAS WE FOCUS ON.”

So what is the first step in this process?

1. The preparation of the home. Homes that are prepared well for the market, often referred to as “turnkey homes,” are selling for 5% to 7% more than the rest of the homes on the market. There is more demand for these homes simply because the average buyer is using every last penny just to buy the home. They typically don’t have a lot of funds left over for remodeling or repairs.

When it comes to preparing the home, the first thing we want to do is an upgrade analysis. We’ll take a look at your home and find out where we can put money in and get a big return. We’ve had a lot of success putting $2,0000, $5,000, or $10,000 into a home and getting $10,000, $15,000, or $20,000 in return. We’re getting anywhere from a 200% to 400% return when we strategically put money into a home like this.

The second important piece of preparing your home to sell for more is to get the inspection done upfront. Once you receive an offer on your property, 80% of the negotiating power flips to the buyer. They get to have their own inspections, make their own requests, and get their own estimates. By getting an inspection done before you list, we can find out what’s wrong with the home and get one of our contractors to repair it at a third of what the buyer’s contractor would charge.

If you want to know what particular cosmetic updates or improvements we recommend, be sure to check out one of our past videos about the 5 home improvements to boost your home’s value or the five key updates you can make to boost your home’s curb appeal.

If you have any other questions for us or you’re thinking about buying or selling a home, don’t hesitate to reach out and give us a call or send us an email. Stay tuned for part two of this series, where we’ll talk about presenting your home to the market.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/Videos/2017/Los+Gatos+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+To+Sell+Your+Home+For+More+Money+%2528Part+1%2529.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/Videos/2017/Los+Gatos+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+To+Sell+Your+Home+For+More+Money+%2528Part+1%2529.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

How are we able to consistently sell homes for up to 18% over the market average? Here are the first two steps.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Jennings</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

How are we able to consistently sell homes for up to 18% over the market average? Here are the first two steps.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Silicon Valley, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Should You Sell your Home or Buy a New One First?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-juggle-two-transactions-at-once.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Brett Jennings</author>
        <pubDate>2017-08-08 08:42:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/Videos/2017/Los+Gatos+Real+Estate+Agent-+Selling+When+Buying+a+New+Home.mp4</guid>
        <description>

How can you sell a home when you also want to buy another? Today, we’ll go over four options.


Considering Buying? Click here for gateway access to MLS
Considering Selling? Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation
Click here to access off-site properties


Juggling two real estate transactions can seem like a daunting task. In fact, one of my most
frequently asked questions is about how to sell a home while also wanting to buy another.

Many people are confused about the right way to approach a situation like this. Should you buy first or should you sell first?

Truthfully, there are four ways you can navigate this kind of situation.

The first way is by having something called a contingent purchase. What this means is that when you go out onto the market, find a home you like, and make an offer, you will include a condition on your offer that states that it is contingent upon you listing and selling your home.

To put it simply, this tells the seller that your offer will only be valid in the event that you are successful in listing and selling your own home.

However, with Silicon Valley currently in a seller’s market, buyers are facing a lot of competition. Any home you place an offer on will likely be receiving several other offers that are free of contingencies. Unfortunately, this puts your offer at a disadvantage.

The second route also has to deal with contingencies. However, with this option, you sell your home first. In a contingent sale, you, as the seller, would tell the buyer whose offer you’ve chosen that you will only proceed with selling your home once you have successfully closed on another, yourself.

“COMPLETING TWO TRANSACTIONS ONE AFTER ANOTHER MAY BE EASIER THAN YOU THINK.”

While this still isn’t the best option, it is better than the first. Sellers have a lot more power to utilize these kinds of stipulations in today’s current market.

Even though this second route is better than the first, our next option is even better still.

A bridge loan is another way you can achieve the feat of completing two transactions one after another. With this solution, you will get pre-approved for your new home while taking equity from your old to help with financing. The drawback to this option, though, is that it will require you to have quite a bit of income.

Finally, you might also consider negotiating a rent-back. By taking this route, you’ll place your home on the market first. This is the most common option and is also very, very effective.

Basically, when you receive an offer on your home, you’ll negotiate with the buyer on an amount of time during which you can rent back your property while looking for your next.

We’ve personally helped dozens, if not hundreds, of homeowners using this process. Completing two transactions one after another may be easier than you think.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/Videos/2017/Los+Gatos+Real+Estate+Agent-+Selling+When+Buying+a+New+Home.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/Videos/2017/Los+Gatos+Real+Estate+Agent-+Selling+When+Buying+a+New+Home.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

How can you sell a home when you also want to buy another? Today, we’ll go over four options.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Jennings</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

How can you sell a home when you also want to buy another? Today, we’ll go over four options.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Silicon Valley, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>4 Ways to Get Multiple Offers When Selling Your Home</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/4-ways-to-get-multiple-offers-when.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Brett Jennings</author>
        <pubDate>2017-07-03 10:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

If you want to generate multiple offers for your listing, I have four tips to help you get there.


Considering Buying? Click here for gateway access to MLS
Considering Selling? Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation
Click here to access off-site properties


There are four things to consider to get multiple offers for your home when you put it on the market.

First, you have to prepare your home for sale. Do all the things you’re seeing in some of the best-looking homes on the market. Well-prepared homes are selling for a premium of 5% to 7% more than their asking price. They’re also the homes most frequently getting multiple offers. Some tasks you can do include decluttering, sprucing up your curb appeal and landscaping, and touching up on your home’s painting.

Second, price your home for value. By this, I mean position your home in the market by looking at what other homes are listed and where they’re priced. Your home needs to be the best-looking and best-priced home in order to generate multiple offers, and that typically means pricing lower than your competition.

“MULTIPLE OFFER STRATEGIES ONLY WORK IN A LOW-INVENTORY MARKET.”

Third, set an offer deadline. Tell buyers that they can come with offers, but you won’t review any of them until your deadline, which will be seven to 10 days after (ideally) two full weekends of open houses. Our research tells us this is when your home’s marketing peaks with the amount of buyer traffic.

Lastly, know the market before employing this strategy. Multiple offer strategies only work in a low-inventory market. Fortunately in Silicon Valley, we’ve had chronically low inventory, so many listings often end up with multiple offers. There is some seasonality to our market, though, which tends to create a lull near the end of summer.

Also, know what the trends are in our market. Are prices rising, flattening, or falling? Typically, this strategy works best in a rising market, or when prices are steady.

If you have any questions about how to garner multiple offers for your home or you’re thinking about putting your home on the market and need help with a preparation plan, please don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d be glad to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

If you want to generate multiple offers for your listing, I have four tips to help you get there.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Jennings</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

If you want to generate multiple offers for your listing, I have four tips to help you get there.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Silicon Valley, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>5 Ways to Win a Multiple Offer Situation in Silicon Valley</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/5-ways-to-win-multiple-offer-situation.html</link>
        
          <category>Silicon Valley Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Brett Jennings</author>
        <pubDate>2017-06-13 10:50:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/+Videos/2017/June/Los+Gatos+Real+Estate+Agent-+5+Ways+to+Win+a+Multiple+Offer+Situation+in+Silicon+Valley.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you want to win the bid in a multiple offer situation for a Silicon Valley, consider these five things.


Considering Buying? Click here for gateway access to MLS
Considering Selling? Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation
Click here to access off-site properties


If you want to buy a Silicon Valley home but you find yourself in a multiple offer situation, there are a few select things you can do to ensure you win the home you want. Consider these five things:

1. Know the competition: Your agent should try to find out how many bids you’re competing against and how many disclosures packages have been downloaded. About a quarter to a third of the number of disclosure packages downloaded, will indicate how many offers you can expect to face.

2. Know the market: What’s the average list-to-sales price ratio in the neighborhood for the two or three most recent home sales? If homes there are selling for tens of thousands of dollars over asking price, you want to be prepared to offer that much over list price. This might make you concerned about overpaying, but in a market where values have appreciated by 10% a year, you’ll easily recoup that extra 2% you’re offering in a few months.

“REMOVE AS MANY CONTINGENCIES AS POSSIBLE TO MAKE YOUR OFFER MORE ENTICING.”

3. Consider removing as many contingencies as possible when writing your offer: If you’re working with a lender, get a full loan approval so you can make an offer with no loan contingencies. If you have a property contingency, you have a couple options. If the seller has provided inspections, review them first. If not, ask the seller’s agent if you can do your inspections before making an offer. That way when the time comes to make an offer, you won’t need an appraisal contingency or a loan contingency.

4. Get personal: Write a personal letter to the seller telling them why you love their house and how excited your family is to live there. You’d be amazed at how effective this is. We’ve seen scenarios where a letter was the tipping point that caused our buyers to win the bid despite not even being the highest dollar bid.

5. If you don’t win the bid, get a written backup offer in place: Offer prices can escalate quickly in these situations, and sometimes that No. 1 buyer backs out of the deal. A written backup offer will put you first in line if that happens.

This all works if you have a great agent working on your behalf. If you’d like to talk more about buying a home in our market or you’re thinking of selling your house, give me a call or send me an email soon. I’d love to speak with you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/+Videos/2017/June/Los+Gatos+Real+Estate+Agent-+5+Ways+to+Win+a+Multiple+Offer+Situation+in+Silicon+Valley.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/+Videos/2017/June/Los+Gatos+Real+Estate+Agent-+5+Ways+to+Win+a+Multiple+Offer+Situation+in+Silicon+Valley.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

If you want to win the bid in a multiple offer situation for a Silicon Valley, consider these five things.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Jennings</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

If you want to win the bid in a multiple offer situation for a Silicon Valley, consider these five things.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Silicon Valley, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Join Our Client Concierge Club</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/join-our-client-concierge-club.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Brett Jennings</author>
        <pubDate>2016-03-24 11:03:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/Los+Gatos+Real+Estate+Agent+-+Join+Our+Concierge+Club.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Lately, many people have asked us for recommendations for an architect, contractor, designer, landscaper, and CPA. Of course, we know great professionals we can hook you up with. In fact, we have a particular resource better than Angie’s List, Craigslist, and Diamonds Certified,


Considering Buying? Click here for gateway access to MLS
Considering Selling? Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation
Click here to access off-site properties


Over the last eight years, we’ve curated a preferred vendor list for the surrounding Los Gatos area. We want to share this list with you. It’s easy! Just text BJREX to 38470. You’ll receive a link to download our Homekeepr, complete with the five-star vendor list.

Additionally, the app will connect you with our exclusive Client Concierge Club. It’s an amazing group reserved for our previous clients, friends, and family. It includes some fun events and giveaways throughout the year. Most importantly, it’ll offer you discounts on premium home goods and services from notable brands including Wayfair, Restoration Hardware, Sonos Audio, and Vivint Home Security.

“THE APP WILL CONNECT YOU WITH OUR CLIENT CONCIERGE CLUB.”

As a token of our appreciation, we’ll send you a Client Concierge Club card preloaded with $5 Starbucks credit. This is our way to express our appreciation for your endorsements, referrals, and overall support. Don’t miss out on a free cup of coffee and more savings!

If you have a question about real estate in the surrounding Los Gatos area, give me a call or send me an email. I’d be happy to serve your local real estate needs!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/Los+Gatos+Real+Estate+Agent+-+Join+Our+Concierge+Club.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/Los+Gatos+Real+Estate+Agent+-+Join+Our+Concierge+Club.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Lately, many people have asked us for recommendations for an architect, contractor, designer, landscaper, and CPA. Of course, we know great professionals we can hook you up with. In fact, we have a particular resource better than Angie’s List, Craigslist, and Diamonds Certified,

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Jennings</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Lately, many people have asked us for recommendations for an architect, contractor, designer, landscaper, and CPA. Of course, we know great professionals we can hook you up with. In fact, we have a particular resource better than Angie’s List, Craigslist, and Diamonds Certified,

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Silicon Valley, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Power of Partnership</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/exciting-changes-in-our-business.html</link>
        
          <category>Brett Jennings Real Estate Experts</category>
        
        <author>Brett Jennings</author>
        <pubDate>2015-12-11 13:20:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/Los+Gatos+Real+Estate+Agent+Exciting+Changes+in+Our+Business.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today, we wanted to let you know about some great things that are happening in our business. Frank Herman has joined us here at Keller Williams in Los Gatos!


Considering Buying? Click here for gateway access to MLS
Considering Selling? Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation
Click here to access off-site properties


I’ve known Frank for a number of years. He’s a very accomplished Realtor. Frank’s an expert in investment real estate, and I’m an expert in marketing and negotiation. We looked at our two businesses and thought we could serve both of our clients at a higher level by teaming up.

You’ll hear from both Frank and I in the coming months. This is only the beginning! We’ll give you the latest real estate information through our video blog. If you have any questions, give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/Los+Gatos+Real+Estate+Agent+Exciting+Changes+in+Our+Business.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/Los+Gatos+Real+Estate+Agent+Exciting+Changes+in+Our+Business.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Today, we wanted to let you know about some great things that are happening in our business. Frank Herman has joined us here at Keller Williams in Los Gatos!

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Jennings</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today, we wanted to let you know about some great things that are happening in our business. Frank Herman has joined us here at Keller Williams in Los Gatos!

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Silicon Valley, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Is the Best Time of Year to Sell Your Home?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/advantages-of-selling-in-winter.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Brett Jennings</author>
        <pubDate>2015-11-30 10:58:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/Los+Gatos+Real+Estate+Agent+Surprising+Advantages+of+Selling+in+Winter.mp4</guid>
        <description>

With real estate prices peaking, many of you who are considering selling your home or moving up into a bigger one are asking “When is the best time to sell my home?” The answer to the question may surprise you.


Considering Buying? Click here for gateway access to MLS
Considering Selling? Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation
Click here to access off-site properties


If you’ve been waiting until the spring to list your home, you are going to want to take a look at these numbers. Redfin, the largest online real estate brokerage in the country, compiled two year’s worth of data across 19 metro markets and here is what the data says. Homes that are listed during the winter are:
◘ 9% more likely to sell
◘ Sell in an average of one week faster
◘ Sell for 1.2% more money

This is contrary to conventional wisdom, which says that listing your home in the spring is the best time because of all the buyers that are out looking at that time of year. While it’s true that there aren’t as many buyers during the winter, the buyers that do shop in the winter are often more motivated and serious.

The buyers out looking this time of year are what we call “life event buyers.” They are people that are buying because of job relocations, deaths in the family, or the birth of a new child, among other reasons. These are people who need to buy, as opposed to most buyers during the spring and summer months who just want to buy. If you can be flexible with your timing, listing around this time of year can be of great advantage to you.

If you’re considering selling in 2016, you may want to consider advancing your timeline to take advantage of this prime time in the market. Interest rates are also going to rise this year, which may put a dampening effect on prices.

If you would like us to evaluate your personal situation, please reach out to us. We would be happy to do a complimentary consultation, as well as an equity analysis to see how much money you have in your property that you can take on to whatever your next chapter may be.

If you have any other questions, don’t hesitate to give us a call. We will be right here, ready to help you create a better life through real estate.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/Los+Gatos+Real+Estate+Agent+Surprising+Advantages+of+Selling+in+Winter.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/Los+Gatos+Real+Estate+Agent+Surprising+Advantages+of+Selling+in+Winter.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

With real estate prices peaking, many of you who are considering selling your home or moving up into a bigger one are asking “When is the best time to sell my home?” The answer to the question may surprise you.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Jennings</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

With real estate prices peaking, many of you who are considering selling your home or moving up into a bigger one are asking “When is the best time to sell my home?” The answer to the question may surprise you.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Silicon Valley, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Three Things to Keep in Mind When Selecting a Mover</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/three-things-to-keep-in-mind-when-selecting-a-mover.html</link>
        
        <author>Brett Jennings</author>
        <pubDate>2015-08-28 10:40:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/Los+Gatos+Real+Estate+Agent+What+to+look+for+when+hiring+a+moving+company.mp4</guid>
        <description>
Today, Scott Cramer from Ace Relocation joins us to discuss three things to look for when selecting a moving company.


Considering Buying? Click here for gateway access to MLS
Considering Selling? Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation
Click here to access off-site properties


1. Pay attention to the mover’s reputation. Do your research. Read customer reviews, and make sure everyone that you allow into your home is on the up and up.

2. Make sure the company has workers’ compensation insurance. This ensures that if someone gets injured on the job, the company will not sue the homeowners.

3. The mover should care. You want them to care for the home and the goods they are moving.

With Ace Relocation, the home itself will be protected by rug and hardwood floor covers, and everything will be wrapped appropriately. Anything that’s breakable will be covered first with cardboard, then pad-wrapped, and then shrink-wrapped.

That’s why we recommend Scott Cramer and Ace Relocation to all of our clients. Ace Relocation is a great moving company. To contact Scott, call (408) 605-7412 or email SCramer@AceRelocation.com.

As always, if you have any questions for us, give us a call or send us an email. We’d be happy to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/Los+Gatos+Real+Estate+Agent+What+to+look+for+when+hiring+a+moving+company.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/Los+Gatos+Real+Estate+Agent+What+to+look+for+when+hiring+a+moving+company.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>
Today, Scott Cramer from Ace Relocation joins us to discuss three things to look for when selecting a moving company.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Jennings</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>
Today, Scott Cramer from Ace Relocation joins us to discuss three things to look for when selecting a moving company.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Silicon Valley, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Google & Apple Pushing Home Prices Higher</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/los-gatos-real-estate-agent-big-changes.html</link>
        
          <category>Silicon Valley Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Brett Jennings</author>
        <pubDate>2015-04-16 14:52:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/Los+Gatos+Real+Estate+Agent+Google+and+Apple+bringing+big+changes+to+the+area.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today, I want to discuss how Google and Apple will push home prices higher this year and beyond.


Considering Buying? Click here for gateway access to MLS
Considering Selling? Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation
Click here to access off-site properties


The #1 drive of home appreciation is job growth. The precursor of job growth is the leasing of commercial office space; when big companies plan to hire more people, the first thing they do is go out and find more space. Recently, I spoke with Phil Maloney, the nation’s top commercial leasing broker, and he shared some interesting facts:
• Google has recently acquired 5 million square feet of new office space
• Apple added 100,000 square feet of new office space per week in 2014
• There will be a rough total of 10 million square feet of office space that will house 50,000-60,000 workers

To put these numbers in perspective: last year, Silicon Valley as a whole created around 42,000 jobs. With Google and Apple looking to add up to 60,000 new jobs in the coming years, these two giants alone are going to create more than the whole area did in 2014! With Silicon Valley thriving, you can expect to see a strong economy that will continue to create jobs, which will effectively push up both wages and the price of property!

“With Silicon Valley thriving, you can expect to see a strong economy that will continue to create jobs.”

If you’re a buyer, the sooner you act, the better. The price and payment of the home you want are only going to rise. If you’re a seller, it’s important to realize that rising prices will hit a ceiling; we’re in a seller’s market right now, so there’s no better time to get top dollar for your home! Give us a call or shoot us a quick email if you have any additional questions about how Google and Apple will push home prices higher in the years to come. We would love to hear from you!

As always, we’ll be right here, ready to help you create a better life through real estate!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/Los+Gatos+Real+Estate+Agent+Google+and+Apple+bringing+big+changes+to+the+area.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/Los+Gatos+Real+Estate+Agent+Google+and+Apple+bringing+big+changes+to+the+area.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Today, I want to discuss how Google and Apple will push home prices higher this year and beyond.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Jennings</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today, I want to discuss how Google and Apple will push home prices higher this year and beyond.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Silicon Valley, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>One Real Estate Mistake That Can Cost You a Fortune</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/one-real-estate-mistake-that-can-cost.html</link>
        
        <author>Brett Jennings</author>
        <pubDate>2015-02-19 16:02:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/Los+Gatos+Real+Estate+Agent+Save+your+family+from+unnecessary+expenses.mp4</guid>
        <description>

In the real estate world, those with the most knowledge are usually the most successful. Today we are delighted to be joined by Rich Dayton, a certified specialist in real estate trust planning and probate law, to talk about a simple mistake that homeowners make without realizing it, a mistake that could end up costing you tens of thousands of dollars.


Considering Buying? Click here for gateway access to MLS
Considering Selling? Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation
Click here to access off-site properties


So, what is this mistake? Well, according to Rich, 90% of people in our country do not have any form of estate plan in place and that can be a very serious problem for them. If you don’t have something like a living trust, power of attorney, or health care directive setup, you can be subject to probate. Probate is based on the gross value of a property. With the average price of a property in Silicon Valley at about $1 million, your probate could run up to $50,000.

If you have a plan in place with the help of a professional like Rich, it’s a fraction of the cost of the risk you are exposing yourself to without one. It also helps your family in case of untimely death, and takes any extra worrying out for them.

“With the average price of a property in Silicon Valley at about $1 million, your probate could run up to $50,000.”

One other problem that many people have has to do with a revocable living trust. Many times, people fail to fund the real estate, with the title of the property in the name of the trustees rather than in their individual names.

Another thing to watch out for is exposing your property through refinancing. Most mortgage companies require you to take the property out of your trust, put it in your name, and if you don’t take the action to affirmatively put it back in, you’ve exposed that property to probate again.

If you want to avoid these problems, give Rich a call. He can also offer you a complimentary consultation, click the link in the video to sign up!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/Los+Gatos+Real+Estate+Agent+Save+your+family+from+unnecessary+expenses.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/Los+Gatos+Real+Estate+Agent+Save+your+family+from+unnecessary+expenses.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

In the real estate world, those with the most knowledge are usually the most successful. Today we are delighted to be joined by Rich Dayton, a certified specialist in real estate trust planning and probate law, to talk about a simple mistake that homeowners make without realizing it, a mistake that could end up costing you tens of thousands of dollars.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Jennings</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

In the real estate world, those with the most knowledge are usually the most successful. Today we are delighted to be joined by Rich Dayton, a certified specialist in real estate trust planning and probate law, to talk about a simple mistake that homeowners make without realizing it, a mistake that could end up costing you tens of thousands of dollars.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Silicon Valley, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Zillow Isn't Telling You Could Cost You</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/los-gatos-real-estate-agent-zillow.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Brett Jennings</author>
        <pubDate>2014-07-11 08:29:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/Los+Gatos+Real+Estate+Agent-+Should+You+Trust+Zillow%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

As one of the top real estate websites in the country, Zillow plays an important role in our industry. On the one hand, it’s a good source for Los Gatos real estate trends. On the other hand, it isn’t so good at providing accurate value estimates or up-to-date information on homes for sale.


Considering Buying? Click here for gateway access to MLS
Considering Selling? Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation
Click here to access off-site properties


Why is Zillow not as accurate as people expect?

For starters, Zillow gathers some data from tax records and some data from the Multiple Listing Service (MLS). While the MLS is the true, accurate market for real estate data, tax records are not a reliable source for home evaluations. For instance, sales that occur off market, such as inter-family transfers, cause property to sell for less than full market value. **This skews the data enough to make the Zestimate nothing more than a broad estimate. **

If you’re trying to sell your home in Los Gatos, Willow Glen or Saratoga, Zillow isn’t going to be much help getting an accurate value estimate. Zillow’s algorithm only accounts for things like bedroom and bathroom count and the square footage of the property in relation to the particular neighborhood’s market values. If you’ve made gorgeous improvements to your home - marble counter tops, new cabinets, etc. - they won’t be factored into the Zestimate. This could cause your home to be undervalued by as much as 10-15%.

If you are looking to buy a home, you need to know that Zillow’s data is typically delayed anywhere from 24-72 hours. At best, Zillow is a convenient starting point. Once you have your feet on the street shopping for a home, it’s time to hire a local expert. We’re here to help with real-time market information and listings.

As always, give us a call if you are looking to buy or sell a home in Los Gatos, Willow Glen or Saratoga, or anywhere in the Silicon Valley area. We would be happy to provide you with the most updated and accurate information.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/Los+Gatos+Real+Estate+Agent-+Should+You+Trust+Zillow%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/Los+Gatos+Real+Estate+Agent-+Should+You+Trust+Zillow%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

As one of the top real estate websites in the country, Zillow plays an important role in our industry. On the one hand, it’s a good source for Los Gatos real estate trends. On the other hand, it isn’t so good at providing accurate value estimates or up-to-date information on homes for sale.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Jennings</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

As one of the top real estate websites in the country, Zillow plays an important role in our industry. On the one hand, it’s a good source for Los Gatos real estate trends. On the other hand, it isn’t so good at providing accurate value estimates or up-to-date information on homes for sale.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Silicon Valley, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Finance Major Home Improvement Projects</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-finance-major-home-improvement.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Brett Jennings</author>
        <pubDate>2014-06-02 11:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/Silicon+Valley+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+Much+Will+Your+Dream+Home+Cost+You%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

How to Finance Major Home Improvement Projects


Considering Buying? Click here for gateway access to MLS
Considering Selling? Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation
Click here to access off-site properties


In our last blog we spoke about the five most valuable home improvement projects that you can do on your home (see below). We realize that some of these projects can get pricey, and because of that we’re going to provide you with ways in which you can fund them.

Most of the repairs that we mentioned in the last video would cost $50,000 or less, and are all common fix-ups that you would do prior to putting your home on the market. If you do plan to sell your home after making these repairs, my team does offer an in-house financing plan. These costs can be carried through the close of Escrow so they don’t have to come directly out of your pocket.

Other options for funding projects (less than $50K) would be to take out a Home Equity Line of Credit (HELOC). This is basically a second mortgage that goes behind your first mortgage and allows you to draw money for your project.

For home repairs that are a little more extensive ($50K-$250K), such as when someone wants to mold a property into their dream home, you will have a few different financing options. You can either take a HELOC like we have just talked about, or you can opt for a Cash Out Refinance Option. The major downside to a HELOC is that the loan is adjustable, so as the loan amount increases you might pay more and we are also in a market with rising interest.

The Cash Out Loan is preferable for these projects because it is fixed-rate loan and it’s all one simple payment. If your current loan is above 4% then the Cash Out Loan is probably your better option, and if it is in the low 3’s then a HELOC is probably a better consideration.

The third type of project we’re seeing in Silicon Valley is where people are completely rebuilding their homes in order to compete with soaring home values of newly-built properties. You would want to consider a Construction Loan in this case. Generally these projects are $500,000 and more. These projects are highly expensive and require special funding.

Hopefully this information has been useful to you. If you’re interested in learning more about this type of financing or would like to speak with me about Silicon Valley real estate, then please do not hesitate to give me a call.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/Silicon+Valley+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+Much+Will+Your+Dream+Home+Cost+You%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/Silicon+Valley+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+Much+Will+Your+Dream+Home+Cost+You%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

How to Finance Major Home Improvement Projects

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Jennings</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

How to Finance Major Home Improvement Projects

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Silicon Valley, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>5 Home Improvements to Boost Your Home Value</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/silicon-valley-real-estate-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
          <category>Most Popular</category>
        
        <author>Brett Jennings</author>
        <pubDate>2014-05-21 16:02:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/Silicon+Valley+-+5+Improvements+Garunteed+to+Raise+Your+Home%27s+Value.mp4</guid>
        <description>

5 Improvements Guaranteed to Raise Your Home’s Value


Considering Buying? Click here for gateway access to MLS
Considering Selling? Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation
Click here to access off-site properties


Our topic today comes to us from people asking about the recent increase in home values throughout California and Silicon Valley. I wanted to show you 5 different ways that you can increase your home’s value through home improvements.

1. Front Door: You never get a second chance to make a first impression. A new front door can cost anywhere from $700-$5,000 but on average, you can expect a 125% return on the replacement of a front door.

2. Interior Doors: Interior doors are relatively inexpensive but can add a lot to your home. There is a company in Silicon Valley (Interior Door Replacement Company) that can replace your doors for $100-$200. This is a very inexpensive way to upgrade the look of your home. It’s amazing what new door handles can do as well.

3. Garage Door: This will typically increase your home value and your curb appeal substantially. I recently replaced my aluminum garage door with a wooden one, and it made a world of difference on the curb appeal of my home. This is another project that will return well over 100% of the money invested.

4. Kitchen Remodel: While this is more extensive than my other suggestions, kitchens sell houses. A kitchen remodel can dramatically upgrade the appeal (and market value) of your home. In my opinion, a good kitchen remodel can return 2-3x the cost, making it one of the best investments you can make in your home.

5. Bathroom Remodels: Bathroom and kitchen remodels go hand in hand. Consumers love seeing updated kitchens and modern bathrooms. You can spend as little as $3,000 dollars on a half bathroom, or you can spend as much as $15,000 on a full bathroom remodel. Little changes to your bathroom can also add a lot of value.

If you’re considering a specific project for your Silicon Valley home, be sure to look at that report and also consult with a professional real estate agent. Most remodels don’t raise your home’s value and will cost you both time and money. A local real estate expert can help you determine where your home would benefit the most from key improvements.

Please don’t hesitate to contact us. We’d love to take a look at your property to discuss the improvements you’re considering and how they will affect the value of your home.

How to finance your home improvements

David Lawver and Brett discuss three ways to finance your upgrades.

Please don’t hesitate to contact us. We’d love to take a look at your property to discuss the improvements you’re considering and how they will affect the value of your home.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/Silicon+Valley+-+5+Improvements+Garunteed+to+Raise+Your+Home%27s+Value.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/Silicon+Valley+-+5+Improvements+Garunteed+to+Raise+Your+Home%27s+Value.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

5 Improvements Guaranteed to Raise Your Home’s Value

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Jennings</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

5 Improvements Guaranteed to Raise Your Home’s Value

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Silicon Valley, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Move Up: Buy First or Sell First?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/path-from-current-home-to-new-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Brett Jennings</author>
        <pubDate>2014-04-23 14:48:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

I am back today with David Lawver from Kal Financial discussing how to get from your current home and into your next one. Should you buy first? Should you sell first? Or should you own 2 homes at once?


Considering Buying? Click here for gateway access to MLS
Considering Selling? Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation
Click here to access off-site properties


There are typically 4 ways to get from your existing home to your new one.

1. Temporary Rental: This might be the simplest, but not the most convenient. You sell your home, rent a property for 3-6 months, and then move into the home you eventually purchase. This involves moving twice, which most people like to avoid. This usually leads to other options.

2. Make a Contingent Offer on Your New Home: This means you start by locating your next home, then write into the offer that the purchase of that property is contingent on the sale of your current home. In the market we’re experiencing in Silicon Valley with low inventory and high demand, this offer doesn’t stand a good chance of being accepted.

3. Contingent Sale: In this option you would start by listing your home for sale, but the sale would be contingent on locating and purchasing your next home. Basically, you would tell the buyer who presents the final offer that you can only sell your home once you have found another. This option has a higher possibility of working in our Silicon Valley market, but it still puts you at a disadvantage when you’re buying because your offer would still be contingent on closing escrow on your current home.

4. Sell Your Home and Rent Back until You Buy: In this option you would sell your current property but request that the buyer rent the home back to you while you find your next home. Usually lenders will not allow rent-backs for longer than 60 days, so you have to be swift if you’re going to do this. If you add in the 30-day escrow period, you would have around 90 days to locate and move into a new property, which is manageable with the help of a skilled agent.

The final option would be to utilize a bridge loan. This works best for people who are equity-rich and cash-poor. They get a loan against their equity to provide a down payment on the new purchase. They are then able to buy and close on a home while still living in their existing home. This allows people to sell at their own pace. Neither escrow is contingent upon the other. The downside is that you must qualify for two mortgages.

So, a bridge loan is your best option, but you have to have a large income and great credit. The second best would be to sell your home and then do a rent-back. These are the two best options in our Silicon Valley market, so consult your local real estate expert for the best options if you’re operating outside of our local market.

If you’re nervous about this process, keep in mind that we are willing and capable to provide you with assistance. Feel free to contact me to discuss your situation, or to talk about real estate in Silicon Valley in general.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

I am back today with David Lawver from Kal Financial discussing how to get from your current home and into your next one. Should you buy first? Should you sell first? Or should you own 2 homes at once?

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Jennings</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

I am back today with David Lawver from Kal Financial discussing how to get from your current home and into your next one. Should you buy first? Should you sell first? Or should you own 2 homes at once?

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Silicon Valley, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Move Up: Buy First or Sell First?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/avoid-bidding-wars-find-properties.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Brett Jennings</author>
        <pubDate>2014-04-23 14:48:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/Silicon+Valley+Real+Estate+-+5+Ways+to+Buy+and+Sell+at+the+Same+Time.mp4</guid>
        <description>

How to Purchase When Inventory is Low
Today I’m going to to speak about a problem that a lot of buyers in Silicon Valley have been asking me about lately. Inventory is currently very low in this area, and clients have been asking me how to buy a home with so few properties available. I have three simple things you can do to increase your chances of finding a great home for yourself.


Considering Buying? Click here for gateway access to MLS
Considering Selling? Click here for a FREE Home Price Evaluation
Click here to access off-site properties


1. Get Gateway Access to the MLS: A lot of people only look for homes on websites like Trulia or Zillow, and while these are good resources, they do not provide direct access to the MLS. For a property to show up on Trulia or Zillow, it can take anywhere from 24-72 hours to be uploaded, and in a fast-paced market such as the one here in Silicon Valley, it’s just not fast enough. The MLS will give you the best chance to find up-to-date properties with accurate information on them.

2. Get Access to Off-Market Properties: What I mean by this is that you should be looking at private sellers, builders, developers, or perhaps people that are flipping properties. Here at Bret Jennings Real Estate Experts, we’ve been cultivating a list of more than 100 properties that are not on the MLS. With only 750 properties available on the MLS, our list represents almost 15% of all available inventory in Silicon Valley. Feel free to click the link below to request a copy of our Off-Market List.

3. Be Proactive in Your Search: Whoever you’re working with in your search for real estate, whether it’s yourself or another agent, you need to be proactive in your search. What I mean by this is that your realtor should be engaging in a telemarketing campaign, a direct mail campaign, or even a door knocking campaign. You want to contact any and all potential sellers in your neighborhood so that you can put an offer on a property before it hits the MLS. This way you can make an offer on their home and avoid a bidding war before it goes on the open market. Turn over every stone that you possibly can.

These are three great strategies for finding homes when inventory is low. Also, by finding properties not listed on the MLS you have a better chance of finding a good deal with less competition.

Of course, the best thing that you can do to find yourself a great home is to contact your real estate agent. If you need assistance finding real estate in Silicon Valley, allow me to be your resource. I can be reached at (408) 807-4541 or visit www.TheBrettJenningsTeam.com
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/Silicon+Valley+Real+Estate+-+5+Ways+to+Buy+and+Sell+at+the+Same+Time.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Jennings/Silicon+Valley+Real+Estate+-+5+Ways+to+Buy+and+Sell+at+the+Same+Time.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

How to Purchase When Inventory is Low
Today I’m going to to speak about a problem that a lot of buyers in Silicon Valley have been asking me about lately. Inventory is currently very low in this area, and clients have been asking me how to buy a home with so few properties available. I have three simple things you can do to increase your chances of finding a great home for yourself.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Jennings</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

How to Purchase When Inventory is Low
Today I’m going to to speak about a problem that a lot of buyers in Silicon Valley have been asking me about lately. Inventory is currently very low in this area, and clients have been asking me how to buy a home with so few properties available. I have three simple things you can do to increase your chances of finding a great home for yourself.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Silicon Valley, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Brett Jennings</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Brett Jennings</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Brett Jennings Real Estate Experts - your professional Silicon Valley Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
